Leader Nui?
ヌイリーダー？
Yen Jiang will
イェン・ジャンは
with this
これとともに
speech
スピーチ
is
は
please, China
お願いします、中国
It's fourteen
十四です
once a month for the first time in 2014
2014年に初めて月に1回
But it's the last time in twelve years
でも12年ぶりだ
Because next year will be a new year
来年は新年なので
Say hello to everyone
みんなによろしくお伝えください
I am very pleased to invite Dr. Chen Jindi from the Institute of Chemistry today
本日は化学研究所からチェン・ジンディ博士をお招きできることを大変うれしく思います
To introduce this colorful world
このカラフルな世界を紹介するために
from the traditional rash
従来の発疹から
Optoelectronic technology from craftsmanship to fashion
クラフトマンシップからファッションまでの光電子技術
Then Dr. Chen is now in the Institute of Chemistry
その後、チェン博士は現在化学研究所にいます。
The main areas of the researcher are
研究者の主な分野は次のとおりです。
Organic Optoelectronic Materials
有機光電材料
Including Organic Light Emitting Diodes
有機発光ダイオードを含む
and research and development of organic solar cell materials
有機太陽電池材料の研究開発
Tamkang University
淡江大学
In 1982, he joined the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University.
1982 年に国立台湾大学化学科に入学しました。
I got a master's degree in my laboratory
私は自分の研究室で修士号を取得しました
Then he got military service
それから彼は兵役に就いた
Then went to America in 1987
その後1987年に渡米
the University of Illinois
イリノイ大学
Received Ph.D. in 1992
1992年博士号取得
Then at Caltech
その後カリフォルニア工科大学で
Three years as a postdoctoral fellow
ポスドクとしての3年間
Joined the Institute of Chemistry in 1995
1995年化学研究所入所
Then when everyone is a postdoctoral fellow
そして全員がポスドクになったとき
Ph.D. and postdoctoral
博士号およびポスドク
non-linear optical materials
非線形光学材料
This thing is following the light
こいつは光を追ってる
Visible light is strongly absorbed
可視光線は強く吸収される
After returning to Taiwan in 1995
1995年に台湾に帰国後
The initial research topic was organic light-emitting diodes
当初の研究テーマは有機発光ダイオードでした
Organic light-emitting diodes are now many
有機発光ダイオードは現在たくさんあります
These very colorful materials inside a flat-panel display
フラットパネルディスプレイ内のこれらの非常にカラフルなマテリアル
The electrons emit light and then emit various kinds of light
電子は光を発し、さらにさまざまな光を発します。
Then in the last five or six years, we have been researching solar cell materials
そしてここ5、6年は太陽電池材料の研究を行っています。
Then you know if you want to absorb solar energy
そうすれば、太陽エネルギーを吸収したいかどうかがわかります
That is, all kinds of attractive materials
つまり、あらゆる魅力的な素材
Can absorb sunlight very effectively
太陽光を効果的に吸収できる
So there are some materials related to the color
色に関係する素材がいくつかありますので、
is its specialty
その専門分野です
So the topic of its speech today is this colorful world
今日のスピーチのテーマはこのカラフルな世界です
That Dr. Chen can in 2002
2002 年にチェン博士ができること
Awarded the third Tsinghua Chemical Science, Technology, Culture and Education Foundation
第3回清華化学科学技術文化教育基金賞を受賞
outstanding period
未払い期間
In 2003, he won the Research Works Award for Young Scholars from Academia Sinica
2003 年に中央研究院の若手研究者賞を受賞
In 2004, won the case award of patent and transfer of Academia Sinica in that year
2004年、同年に中央研究院から特許及び譲渡の事例賞を受賞
Therefore, there are more than 100 papers, more than ten patents, and three special books
したがって、100 以上の論文、10 以上の特許、および 3 冊の専門書籍があります。
It is for him to serve as the deputy director of the Institute of Chemistry from 2005 to 2009
彼は 2005 年から 2009 年まで化学研究所の副所長を務めました。
So this subject and even his research specialty
つまり、このトピックと彼の研究の専門分野さえも
So we welcome Dr. Chen to talk about designing the world with warm applause
それでは、温かい拍手をもってチェン博士に世界のデザインについて語ってもらいたいと思います。
Thank you, Peng Fude, for introducing
紹介してくれた彭富徳さん、ありがとう
In fact he was my teacher
実は彼は私の先生でした
He should be called Mr. Peng respectfully.
彼は敬意を持って彭氏と呼ばれるべきです。
Now because everyone is working since graduation
今は卒業してみんな働いているから
So now it is considered to be serving in the same unit
したがって、現在は同じユニットで提供されていると見なされます
have this chance
この機会を持ってください
This was also successfully invited by Mr. Peng.
これも彭氏の誘いに成功した。
Come and make one for everyone before Chinese New Year
旧正月の前にみんなに作ってあげましょう
Such a report of a feast of knowledge
そんな知識の饗宴のレポート
because of the new year
新年のせいで
so i think
だから私は思う
The topic I think is also very suitable for this season
この季節にもぴったりなテーマだと思います
Here are some colorful ones for you
ここにいくつかのカラフルなものがあります
beautiful pattern
美しい模様
After seeing it like this
こうやって見てから
Everyone can go back to celebrate the New Year happily
みんなで楽しく新年を祝いに帰ってください
This is a question of comparing penises
ペニスの比較の問題です
Okay, this topic is
さて、今回の話題は、
Mainly talking about dyes
主に染料の話
Dyes I think everyone knows very well
染料については皆さんよくご存知かと思いますが、
Everyone knows that since childhood
それは子供の頃から誰もが知っています
This is the part about color
ここは色に関する部分です
In fact, this color
実はこの色、
I want to talk about the origin of some history
歴史の起源について話したいと思います
This is what you see
これがご覧のとおりです
inside the disaster of the speech
スピーチの惨状の中で
mentioned this
これについて言及しました
I'll tell you a little bit about the discovery of this color in a moment.
この色の発見については後ほど少しお話します。
The origin of history
歴史の起源
sorry
ごめん
This laser ratio is somewhat
このレーザー比は若干
good this
いいですね、これ
talk about color
要講色彩
In fact, I want to explain a little bit about the origin of this color
実はこの色の由来について少し説明したいと思います
The reason why there are colors on the earth
地球上に色がある理由
Generates a relationship between the sun and the sun
太陽と太陽の関係を生み出す
The basis for this is very simple
この根拠は非常に単純です
In fact this happens this color
実際にはこの色が起こります
One of them is a very famous person
そのうちの一人はとても有名な人です
It's Newton
ニュートンだよ
what about this experiment
この実験はどうですか
The experiment in a forest environment called Newton
ニュートンと呼ばれる森林環境での実験
because you all know
皆さんは知っているから
If you put the sunlight in this mountain forest
この山林に陽光を当てれば
shine on the forest
森を照らす
It can decompose the sunlight into various colors
太陽光をさまざまな色に分解できる
Let's talk about this colorful neon color
このカラフルなネオンカラーについて話しましょう
red orange yellow green blue green purple
赤、オレンジ、黄、緑、青、緑、紫
So in fact sunlight is
つまり、実際には太陽光は
Sources of colors that our human eyes see all over the planet
私たちの人間の目が地球上で見る色の源
from the sun
太陽から
what color
何色
Add all colors of red, orange, yellow, green, blue, green and purple together
赤、オレンジ、黄、緑、青、緑、紫のすべての色を加算します
becomes white
白くなる
so we see sunlight
だから私たちは太陽の光を見ます
Predominantly white light color
主に白色の光の色
Of course this algae turns yellow
もちろんこの藻は黄色になります
will be a bit off
少しずれます
Algae turned yellow will be closer to yellow-orange color
黄色に変わる藻類は黄オレンジ色に近づきます
Among Japanese people, the light color is closer to pure white
日本人にとって光の色は純白に近い
This is because the atmosphere is dry and old sunlight
これは大気が乾燥しており、古い太陽の光が入っているためです。
According to the color of the earth, there are some distorted colors
地球の色に合わせて、歪んだ色もある
produced by the phenomenon of color twisting
色のねじれ現象によって生じる
Humans have five senses
人間には五感があります
Inside the facial features of a person
人の顔の特徴の内側
In fact, only the eyes are responsible for seeing
実際、見る責任を負っているのは目だけです
Seeing things is that our human eyes are able to distinguish
ものを見るということは、私たち人間の目が区別できることです。
Different colors of light come out
いろんな色の光が出てくる
Because of the structural relationship between our eyes and people
私たちの目と人間の構造的な関係により、
This is the reason for the origin of a simple color
シンプルな色の由来はここにある
This visible light sun actually emits a lot
この可視光線、太陽は実際に多くの光を放射します
The radiant energy of different bands comes out
異なる帯域の放射エネルギーが出てくる
Visible light from the sun can only
太陽からの可視光だけでできるのは、
It's just the visible light in a short area
狭い範囲の可視光だけです
What about all the sources of radiation?
すべての放射線源はどうなるのでしょうか?
is very widely distributed
非常に広く分布しています
from what everyone knows
誰もが知っていることから
The ones on the radio are called radio waves
ラジオから出るものを電波といいます
That is a type of energy emitted by sunlight
それは太陽光が発するエネルギーの一種です
Or let's talk about a kind of light wave
あるいは、一種の光の波について話しましょう
Visible light is only in this wide band
可視光はこの広い帯域のみにあります
within a narrow range
狭い範囲内で
What is the shortest possible X-ray and cosmic color line?
可能な限り短い X 線と宇宙の色の線は何ですか?
It is one of the rays emitted by the sun
太陽から発せられる光線の一つです
The fact that our human eyes see the color of objects
私たち人間の目は物の色を認識するという事実
This is about color
これは色の話です
mainly due to two or three factors
主に 2 つまたは 3 つの要因による
We'll actually get to that shortly later
実際にはすぐにそれについて説明します
This basic color is caused by two reasons
この基本的な色には 2 つの理由があります
one is additive color
一つは加法混色です
a color called vanishing
消えるという色
let's look at this first
まずはこれを見てみましょう
This is not an analysis from another angle
これは別の角度からの分析ではありません
what color is this
これは何色ですか
our human eyes
私たち人間の目
see what color is made of
何色でできているか見てみましょう
Burning hot paper of full red lip aperture like sun light
太陽の光のように真っ赤なリップ開口部の熱紙が燃える
If your stuff is transparent
物が透明な場合
All light will pass through
すべての光は通過します
None of the beams will be blocked
どのビームもブロックされません
In this example it means
この例では、それは次のことを意味します
It shoots light except red and orange
赤とオレンジ以外の光を発射します
let it penetrate outside
外側に浸透させます
Everything else will be absorbed
他のものはすべて吸収されます
Then what we see with our eyes is
それでは、私たちが目で見ているものは、
light passing through
通過する光
In the example drawn above the figure
図の上に描かれた例では
This is what our eyes see
これが私たちの目に見えるものです
it's red orange
赤オレンジです
In the middle example
真ん中の例では
It allows the blue and sky blue to pass through
青と空の青を透過させます
At this time, the object we saw
このとき見えた物体は
it's sky blue
空色です
by analogy
一使類推
This thing looks yellow-green
これは黄緑色に見えます
Because this yellow-green light can pass through
この黄緑色の光は透過するので
So what our eyes see
それで、私たちの目に見えるものは
In fact one of the sun's rays
実際、太陽光線の 1 つが
We call it Complementary Color
それを補色といいます
In addition to penetrating
浸透することに加えて、
cause this phenomenon to occur
この現象が起こる原因となる
another one is
もう一つは、
The principle of reflection is the same, resulting in the same effect
反射の原理は同じなので同じ効果が得られます
If you don't have a thing that will be absorbed by your object
物体に吸収されるものが無い場合
then you see all the rays
そうすれば、すべての光線が見えます
See all the principles of red and yellow
赤と黄色の原理をすべて見る
then what you see is white light
そうすればあなたに見えるのは白い光です
same
同じ
If all your other lights except red and orange
赤とオレンジ以外のライトがすべて点灯している場合
no absorption
吸収なし
The red and orange will be reflected by it
赤とオレンジが反射するよ
At this time, what you see will also be red.
このとき、見えるものも赤くなります。
This is explained by the phenomenon of reflection
これは反射現象で説明できます
The color the object renders
オブジェクトがレンダリングする色
It is to make it adhere to the same principle as when penetrating
貫通するときと同じ原理に従わせるためです。
something not absorbed by that thing
その物に吸収されない何か
and be seen by our eyes
そして私たちの目に映ります
That's where the colors we see come from
私たちが見る色はそこから来るのです
this is from
これはからです
So what our eyes see is the color of the object
つまり私たちの目で見えるのは物体の色です
In fact, it is the protection shot of the light shot
実はライトショットのプロテクトショットです
Our Chen's tail is called Hubushe
私たちのチェンの尻尾はフブッシュと呼ばれています
is caused by this reason
これによって引き起こされる
This shield shot causes the color of many objects
このシールドショットは多くのオブジェクトの色を引き起こします
A very important reason for the color of objects
物体の色の非常に重要な理由
what we see most
私たちが最もよく見るもの
Ink sprayed over a watch
時計にインクを吹き付けた
you go buy this ink cartridge
このインクカートリッジを買いに行きます
There will be these three dots on it
これらの 3 つの点があります
this color ink cartridge
この色のインクカートリッジ
It's going to have this cyan, magenta, and yellow dotted on it.
シアン、マゼンタ、イエローが点在します。
What about these three colors?
この３色はどうでしょうか？
It's actually on this color chart
実はこのカラーチャートにあるんです
It's actually the three colors on this side
実はこちら側の3色です
The three colors of Y, M, and C
Y、M、Cの3色
What about these three colors?
この３色はどうでしょうか？
In fact like yellow
実際は黄色っぽい
Actually the complementary color of blue
実は青の補色
What about the cyan color?
シアン色はどうでしょうか？
it is the complementary color of red
それは赤の補色です
Then the color of sheep's head red is the complementary color of green
すると、羊の頭の色は赤で、緑の補色になります。
The red, blue, green
赤、青、緑は
we call it tricolor
私たちはそれをトリコロールと呼びます
What about the three colors?
3色はどうでしょうか？
after being absorbed
吸収された後
you'll see its complementary color
その補色がわかります
It is the three colors of Y, M and C we just talked about
先ほどお話ししたY、M、Cの3色です
In fact we can see that
実際、それがわかります
so-called complementary colors
いわゆる補色
caused this removal
この削除の原因となった
that paint
そのペイント
Will melt, color, this paint and so on
ケミカル、カラー、この塗料など。
all are
全てです
Wujie you because I just saw it before
ウージ君、さっき見たばかりだから
it is not absorbed by it
それは吸収されません
The color after being worn by us
弊社着用後の色です
and it reflects
そしてそれは反映されます
colors not absorbed by it
吸収されない色
The origin of the complementary colors we see
私たちが目にする補色の起源
In fact, on light compensation
実は光補正に関しては
You can do progressive analysis like
次のような進歩的な分析を行うことができます
If you absorb the color of this area
この辺の色を吸い込めば
Just now this area was red and orange
さっきこのエリアは赤とオレンジ色だった
a little yellow in color
少し黄色っぽい色
If the color in this area is absorbed
この部分の色が吸収されると
all your eyes can see
あなたの目はすべて見える
Green Natural Blue
グリーン ナチュラル ブルー
This is called complementary relationship
これを補完関係といいます
So there are three cases
つまり、3つのケースがあります
What we say in terms of triadic colors
三項色について言うこと
There are three situations
3つの状況があります
This is the second case
これは2番目のケースです
put the yellow green blue thin tone in the middle
黄緑青の薄いトーンを真ん中に置く
Your eyes can only see red and blue around it
君の目には周りの赤と青しか見えない
The third is that you put the short wavelength
3つ目は、短い波長を入れることです。
This fine shade of blue green natural color
この素晴らしい色合いの青緑の自然な色
Your eyes can only see long wavelengths
あなたの目は長い波長しか見ることができません
yellow and red
黄色と赤
This is the reason for the complementary color of the object
これが物体の補色となる理由です
That's right, that's how it's explained by industry scholars.
業界学者はそう説明している。
Of course if you absorb all the light colors
もちろん光の色をすべて吸収すれば
what color is that
それは何色ですか
It becomes black in the middle
真ん中が黒くなる
you can't see anything
何も見えない
because all the light is absorbed by the object
すべての光は物体に吸収されるため、
so you can't see any color
だから何の色も見えない
Can't see any color is black
どの色も黒く見えない
So black is also a color
つまり、黒も色なのです
The color with nothing is called black
何もない色を黒と呼ぶ
Alright, this next has to do with chemistry comparisons
さて、次は化学の比較に関係します
This is because I am doing chemistry
化学をやっているからです
We say that these colors come from sunlight
これらの色は太陽光から来ると言われています
But in fact matter
しかし実際問題は
Our place to see is matter
私たちの見る場所が重要です
The substance itself will produce some color
物質自体が何らかの色を生成します
These colors arise entirely from the
これらの色は完全に次のものから生じます。
caused by the basic chemical elements of which a substance is composed
物質を構成する基本的な化学元素によって引き起こされる
then listen to all matter
それならこれですべてを聞いてください
We roughly divide into two categories
大きく分けて2つのカテゴリーに分かれます
called organic materials or inorganic substances
有機物質または無機物質と呼ばれる
How to distinguish between organic and inorganic
有機物と無機物の見分け方
this is in chemistry
これは化学の分野です
We usually use this to distinguish
通常、区別するためにこれを使用します
If you have a lot of
たくさん持っている場合は、
The elements carbon, hydrogen, oxygen, nitrogen
元素の炭素、水素、酸素、窒素
this is called organic matter
これを有機物といいます
like us
私たちのような
The amino acids we eat, the vitamin
私たちが摂取するアミノ酸、ビタミン
Or the sugar we eat, these are made into organic matter
私たちが食べる砂糖も有機物になります
And the fat we eat is still there
そして私たちが食べた脂肪はまだそこにあります
Swallow these elemental things of green oxygen egg
緑色の酸素の卵のこれらの要素を飲み込みます
This stuff is called organic matter
こういうものを有機物といいます
In addition to these few I use black circles
これらのいくつかに加えて、私は黒い丸を使用します
outside of the circled elements
丸で囲まれた要素の外側
The periodic table has more than 100 images in total
周期表には 100 以上の画像があります
100 now has 10 to 110 more elements
100 には 10 ～ 110 個の要素が追加されました
Deduct these elements
これらの要素を差し引く
substances made of other elements
他の元素でできた物質
Inorganic matter
無機物
This substance is divided into two categories
この物質は 2 つのカテゴリーに分類されます
The color is also composed of these materials
色もこれらの素材で構成されています
organic and inorganic
有機と無機
But the reasons for the colors they produce are different
しかし、それらが生み出す色の理由は異なります
This is a substance made up of inorganic elements
これは無機元素から構成される物質です
the colors it makes
それが作る色
actually depends on the size of your composing elements
実際には構成要素のサイズによって異なります
Like this Buddha these are
この仏陀のように、これらは
Lu Shu's substance
魯粛の実体
Buddha is gas
仏陀はガスです
it itself is yellow
それ自体は黄色です
slightly yellow
ほんのり黄色
slightly bigger green
少し大きめのグリーン
that is green
それは緑です
show is liquid
ショーは液体です
but it's orange
でもオレンジです
then click
次にクリックします
turns purple
紫色に変わります
it's bigger
もっと大きいです
The color will vary with the size of this atom
この原子の大きさによって色が変わります
different means i change
違うということは私が変わるということ
Another class is made of these metals
別のクラスはこれらの金属で作られています
made up of ions or elements
イオンまたは元素で構成される
Different ions have different colors
イオンが異なれば色も異なります
For example, like this tire
例えばこのタイヤのように
In fact, white has no color
実は白には色がない
what about this one
これはどうですか
or fall?
それとも落ちる？
is yellow
黄色です
Its color has something to do with its structure
その色はその構造と関係がある
For example, these two are called Falling Frost and Ion
たとえば、これら 2 つは、Falling Frost と Ion と呼ばれます。
It's just that this is a two sticks connected together
これは2本の棒がつながっているだけです
But this structure is different
でもこの構造は違います
Its constituent metal elements are the same
構成金属元素は同じです
But the structurally different relationship
しかし、構造的に異なる関係
cause different colors
色の違いを引き起こす
These are a characteristic of inorganic materials
これらは無機材料の特性です
its color big
色が大きい
What's the depth
深さは何ですか
or different colors
または違う色
depends on the size of the atom
原子の大きさに依存します
or its structure
またはその構造
to make an impact
影響を与えるために
This is an inorganic material
これは無機材料です
Organic materials as I just said
先ほども言いましたが、有機材料
The whole medium is composed of elements in carbon, oxygen and nitrogen
培地全体は炭素、酸素、窒素の元素で構成されています
its color composition
その色の構成
In fact, with these carbon-carbon doubles
実際、これらの炭素-炭素二重構造により、
If there is no carbon-carbon double piece
カーボンカーボンダブルピースでない場合
all organic matter
これらすべての有機物
usually no color
通常は色がありません
is transparent
透明です
The shade of this color is
この色の色合いは、
Red, blue, green?
赤、青、緑？
Depends on the amount of this carbon-carbon double
この炭素-炭素二重構造の量に依存します
Let's talk about this carbon-carbon double piece
このカーボンとカーボンのダブルピースについて話しましょう
it has beat electrons
それはビート電子を持っています
beat more electrons
より多くの電子を打ち負かす
your color will be darker
あなたの色はもっと暗くなります
The color will be longer wavelength
色は長波長になります
It is the direction of the red offset
赤いオフセットの方向です
it may have been blue at first
最初は青だったかもしれない
later turned green
その後緑色になりました
may be yellow
黄色かもしれない
Then there is orange red
続いてオレンジレッドです
The longer the wavelength of the color
色の波長が長ければ長いほど
So I beat the number of electrons more and more
だからどんどん電子の数を超えていくんだ
while there is a proportional increase
比例的に増加する一方で
as organic and inorganic compounds
有機化合物と無機化合物として
The color produced is actually not the same principle
生成される色は実際には同じ原理ではありません
But the result is the same
しかし結果は同じです
Causes the appearance of colors in visible light
可視光で色の出現を引き起こす
Our eyes can perceive this visible light
私たちの目はこの可視光を認識できます
So people are the reason why they can see colors
つまり、人が色を見ることができる理由は、
Although different substances
物質は違うのに
the principle is the same
原理は同じです
Let me give you an example soon
早速例を挙げてみましょう
Like the ones pictured here
ここに描かれているもののように
all organic matter
すべての有機物
And these substances actually have different colors
そしてこれらの物質は実際にはさまざまな色を持っています
for example this
たとえばこれ
This looks like the shortest molecule
これが一番短いようです
its absorbing wavelength
その吸収波長
It's actually the shortest of the four.
実は4つの中では一番短いんです。
The location is probably in this place
場所はおそらくこの場所です
It absorbs blue light
ブルーライトを吸収してくれる
So our eyes see this
だから私たちの目はこれを見ます
Substances that absorb blue light
ブルーライトを吸収する物質
In fact, it will appear more or less yellowish
実際には、多かれ少なかれ黄色っぽく見えます
color appears
色が出る
This one is slightly longer
こちらの方が少し長めです
Take more electrons
より多くの電子を取り込みます
Its absorption wavelength will be slightly longer
吸収波長が若干長くなる
It absorbs mainly green light
主に緑色の光を吸収します
Complementary colors that our eyes see
私たちの目に見える補色
is to show a color like this carambola
このゴレンシのような色を見せることです
monodentate pile
単座杭
If it continues to grow
このまま成長し続ければ
Its absorption wavelength becomes more and more to the right
吸収波長は右に行くほど大きくなります
Go ahead, this side absorbs the yellow-orange color
どうぞ、こちら側が黄オレンジ色を吸収します
The color it presents at this time
今回ご紹介するカラーは
It will be the color of the complementary color below, Iron Blue
下の補色の色になります、アイアンブルー
And finally if it hides to a certain extent
そして最後にある程度隠れたら
it absorbs red light
赤い光を吸収します
At this time, the substance will show a green luster.
このとき、物質は緑色の光沢を示します。
This is exactly a rendering of a complementary color
まさに補色の表現です
Okay, this is about the color
さて、色の話です
I'm starting to tell the history of this color discovery
この色の発見の歴史を語り始めます
In this so-called chemical technology
このいわゆる化学技術では
or before technology
あるいはテクノロジー以前
Human beings can get colors from nature
人間は自然から色を得ることができる
I saw this here and found a few photos for everyone to see.
ここでこれを見て、みんなに見てもらえるようにいくつかの写真を見つけました。
The most primitive and primitive bibliophile
最も原始的で原始的な愛書家
It's always written in the book
いつも本に書いてある
The source of the most original color is taken from nature
最もオリジナルな色の源は自然から採取されます
For example, this ingredient
例えばこんな成分
This is called sporite
これを胞子状といいます
It's the color that produces that orange-red color
それはオレンジがかった赤を生み出す色です
There is another one called Zheshi
もう一つ「Zheshi」と呼ばれるものがあります。
this translated word
この翻訳された言葉
This color is a stone showing this dark purple color
この色はこの濃い紫色を示す石です
so you can see this stone age
そうすればこの石器時代を見ることができます
The colors painted on the walls of this cave
この洞窟の壁に描かれた色は
last saved until now
今まで最後に保存された
Why do you still see the pattern caused by these two colors?
これら 2 つの色によって引き起こされるパターンが依然として表示されるのはなぜですか?
Because at that time it was possible to obtain colors from nature
当時は自然から色を得ることができたので、
Probably the most common are these two colors
おそらく最も一般的なのはこの2色です
so you look at this mural
それでこの壁画を見てください
Most of them are renderings of these two colors
それらのほとんどはこれら 2 色のレンダリングです
Then this is all things from the stone age
それでは、これはすべて石器時代のものです
After the emergence of human culture
人類文化の出現後
marl culture like ingal
インガルのようなマール文化
Or China's ice cat swimming that painted
あるいは中国のアイスキャットが泳ぐ絵を描いた
The color painted on the artist's face
アーティストの顔に描かれた色
with egypt
エジプトと
Egypt is one of these major civilizations
エジプトはこれらの主要文明の一つです
You can see the color it takes inside
内部の色がわかります
Most of them are biased towards this orange
ほとんどの人はこのオレンジに偏っています
or this pleated red color
またはこのプリーツの赤い色
because at that time
なぜならその時は
The source of the most accessible colors
最も親しみやすい色の源
is the material from these colors
この色から生まれる素材です
while the color material itself provides the most
色素材自体が最大限の効果を発揮します
these two colors
この二色
you go to the book
あなたは本に行きます
the book will tell you
本が教えてくれるでしょう
this ever
これまで
the first human way
最初の人類の道
synthetic artificial coloring
合成人工着色料
It's in this pharaoh's tomb
それはこのファラオの墓の中​​にあります
see this blue substance
この青い物質を見てください
Because this blue substance does not exist in nature
この青い物質は自然界には存在しないので、
It is artificially synthesized
人工的に合成されたものです
Only then can this blue pigment appear
そうして初めてこの青い色素が現れるのです
Here we use the current chemical technology
ここでは現在の化学技術を使用します
The ancient Egyptian
古代エジプト人
How did they go about creating this color?
彼らはどのようにしてこの色を作り出したのでしょうか？
or did he mix it up with three things
それとも彼はそれを3つのものと混同したのでしょうか
processed by Galle
ゴールによって処理される
will be able to generate this thing
これを生み出すことができるだろう
This thing is called Acidic Copper Tears
これは酸性銅の涙と呼ばれるものです
Although it is something like a stone
石のようなものですが、
But this stone is colored
でもこの石には色がある
The color is the natural color
色はナチュラルカラーです
what are these three things it uses
使用する 3 つのものは何ですか
The main source of color is from this
主な色の出典はこちらから
Copper Carbonate
炭酸銅
This thing is called malachite
これはマラカイトと呼ばれるものです
this is in
これは入っています
presumably earlier
おそらくもっと前に
Egypt has a lot of this malachite
エジプトにはこのマラカイトがたくさんあります
So they can get local material
地元の材料を入手できるようにするため
Use this as the source of the color
これを色のソースとして使用します
The colors they make are natural colors
彼らが作る色は自然の色です
Then the quartz sand mixed in
次に珪砂を混ぜます
Quartz sand is the Sally by the sea
石英砂は海のサリーです
main source
主な情報源
that egypt in
あのエジプト
Where
どこ
In North Africa there is a large
北アフリカには大規模な
salad desert
サラダデザート
There are many quartz stones in the salad desert
サラダデザートには水晶石がたくさんあります
So this material is not a problem
したがって、この素材は問題ありません
Then there's the marble
それから大理石です
is the source of carbonated limestone
炭酸石灰岩の原料です
There are many such things in the world of Egypt
エジプトの世界にはそのようなものがたくさんあります
mixing these three things together
この３つを混ぜ合わせて
Originally malachite was this greenish thing
マラカイトはもともとこの緑色のものでした
After the result is processed like this
結果がこのように処理された後
it becomes natural color
自然な色になります
This is the record you can find
これはあなたが見つけることができる記録です
That's the first artificial
それが最初の人造物です
artificially synthesized
人工的に合成された
but it is derived from the infinite substance
しかしそれは無限の物質から派生したものです
There are no such things as carbon, hydrogen, oxygen and nitrogen in it.
そこには炭素、水素、酸素、窒素などは含まれていません。
So it's the rate of fire of the infinite dye
つまり、それは無限染料の発射速度です
Well, those colors, of course this was discovered a long time ago
まあ、それらの色、もちろん、これはずっと前に発見されました
Then it was later used in the creation of this art
その後、このアートの作成に使用されました
I found a few pictures that can be found on the Internet
インターネット上でいくつかの写真を見つけました
For example, the last supper of Jesus
たとえば、イエスの最後の晩餐
I’ve been to this place before, which city in Italy doesn’t matter
この場所には前に行ったことがありますが、イタリアのどの都市でも構いません
Teacher Peng took us there
ペン先生が私たちをそこに連れて行ってくれました
This one is actually a colored lake
これは実際には色のついた湖です
"Monalis" is smiling, look at the fact
「モナリス」が微笑んでいる、ほら見てください
The color has faded over time.
時間の経過とともに色が褪せてきました。
It fades into the color of that yellow coffee color
あの黄色いコーヒー色に消えていく
In fact, it turned out to be a colored substance
実は有色物質だったことが判明
These are famous paintings
これらは有名な絵画です
colorful colors on top
上にはカラフルな色が
Including the more modern ones like this Monet
このモネのようなより現代的なものも含めて
But it is also a painting more than a hundred years ago
しかし、これも100年以上前の絵です
This is also his painting, this one is called
これも彼の絵です、これはと呼ばれるものです
"In Spring Mountain" I can't find out what is the name of this
「春の山にて」これの名前が分かりません
used in these things
こういったものに使われている
These pigment dyes
これらの顔料染料は
But because of the relationship at that time
でもその時の関係のせいで
Because this is an earlier relationship
これは以前からの関係だから
Relationships over a hundred years ago
百年以上前の関係
At that time there was no synthesis technology
当時は合成技術がなかったので、
In fact, they are all raw materials
実はこれらはすべて原材料なのです
e.g. white pigment
例：白色顔料
At that time, it was made of carbon fiber, sulfate fiber
当時は炭素繊維、硫酸塩繊維で作られていました
made of oxidized fiber
酸化繊維で作られた
The yellow one is made of this acid fiber
黄色いのはこの酸性繊維でできています
The blue one is made of this
青いのはこれでできています
This iron complex is composed of
この鉄錯体は次のもので構成されています。
Composed of elements such as red blood fiber and yellow blood fiber
赤血線維や黄血線維などの要素で構成されています。
Green is ash
緑は灰です
Composition of yellow blood fiber, red blood fiber and acid copper
黄血線維、赤血線維、酸性銅の構成
This is all information you can find on the Internet.
これはすべてインターネット上で見つけることができる情報です。
The red color is composed of the fibrous compounds of wood acid and
赤い色は木酸と木の繊維状化合物で構成されています。
And these oxide fibers and copper oxide
そしてこれらの酸化物繊維と酸化銅
These are the early paintings
これらは初期の絵です
Just use these non-productive pigment dyes
これらの非生産的な顔料染料を使用してください。
to do drawing work
絵を描く仕事をする
The fact that these product-free materials are also used in
これらの製品フリー素材が、
The things used in this printing into the newspaper
今回の新聞掲載に使用したもの
This is holding up to now to compare
ここまでの比較になります
Civilization above the printed work we do
私たちが行っている印刷物を超えた文明
Most of the oil used for release
オイルのほとんどはリリースに使用されます
All come from the materials composed of these inorganic substances
すべてはこれらの無機物質から構成される材料から生じます
it will come in a variety of different colors
さまざまな色が登場します
The setting of the inorganic pigment like this
無機顔料の設定はこんな感じ
It is also used in this yellow line of the gang line
このギャングラインの黄色のラインにも使われています
The reason why I mention this is
私がこれについて言及する理由は、
It turns out that the yellow line is mainly made of these
黄色の線は主にこれらで構成されていることがわかります
made of inorganic compounds
無機化合物でできている
like this vulcanized septum or
この加硫スペーサーとか
Acid drop this kind of thing
アシッドドロップってこんな感じ
This thing we just saw earlier
これは先ほど見たばかりのものです
But it's really on the pavement now
でも今は本当に舗道の上にある
There's a lot of these yellow paints too
この黄色のペイントもたくさんあります
made of organic matter
有機物でできている
There is an English text here
ここに英語のテキストがあります
I took it from this website
こちらのサイトからお借りしました
This site says
このサイトにはこう書かれています
Wall-making-Pent Composition
壁作りペント構成
The road style of these yellow board horse lines
この黄色いバンマラインの道路スタイル
the end of its oil
オイルの終わり
what is the composition of the paint
塗料の組成は何ですか
This is explaining the composition of these paints
これはこれらの塗料の組成を説明しています
Usually made of this fluidized terrier or Lutheran
通常、この流動的なテリアまたはルーテル犬で作られています。
But now there are a lot of yellow poultices like this
でも今はこのような黄色い湿布がたくさんあります
is made of this thing
この物でできています
This thing is called Benzidine Yellow
これはベンジジンイエローと呼ばれるものです
Translated into this text is called Lianben Anhuang
このテキストに翻訳すると、「Lianben Anhuang」と呼ばれます。
This is made of an organic substance
これは有機物質でできています
substance with a yellow color
黄色の物質
what about this thing
これはどうですか
Because there are some chemicals
化学物質が入っているので
The release of this same thing is also used in many current cars.
これと同じものがリリースされ、多くの現行車にも採用されています。
paint on car body
車体にペイントする
For example, the yellow color of the little yellow we are talking about
たとえば、私たちが話している小さな黄色の黄色です。
It's actually made of this yellow paint substance
実はこの黄色い塗料でできているんです
And the substance of this paint is actually
そしてこの塗料の正体は実は
Made entirely of organic matter
完全に有機物からできている
you will see it has many
たくさんあることがわかります
Pai Tan Tan double key Pai electronic
パイタンタン ダブルキー パイ電子
There are a lot of rings on this one
このリングにはたくさんのリングがあります
So many rings connected together
たくさんのリングがつながっている
it will appear in color
カラーで表示されます
depends on your chemical structure
化学構造によって異なります
This is all organic matter
これはすべて有機物です
like this one is showing this fuchsia
これはこのフクシアを示しているように
This one is showing this bright red color
これはこの鮮やかな赤色を示しています
This should be an Alfa Romeo sports car
これはアルファロメオのスポーツカーでしょう
This red grilled chicken above
この赤いグリルチキンの上に
Only use organic substances
有機物のみを使用
its color rendering
その演色性
And what about this dark blue substance?
では、この濃い青色の物質はどうでしょうか？
by this car
この車で
is made of this dye
この染料で作られています
Finally there is a bright green
やっと鮮やかな緑が出てきました
this is very colorful
これはとてもカラフルです
like the color of this ninja turtle
このニンジャタートルの色のように
This is made up of the molecules of this macrocycle
これはこの大環状分子の分子で構成されています
These are the organic substances that came out later
これは後から出てきた有機物です
Usually the color of organic matter
通常は有機物の色です
Will be brighter and brighter than the color of inorganic substances
無機物の色より明るく明るくなります
because its color is the intensity of the sunlight it absorbs
なぜなら、その色は吸収した太陽光の強さだからです。
is relatively strong
比較的強いです
So what about Rong Gong's bone-protecting color?
それでは、Rong Gong の骨を保護する色はどうなるのでしょうか?
will be stronger
強くなるだろう
This is how it looks compared to the inorganic material
無機素材と比べるとこんな感じ
So what about organic matter?
では、有機物はどうでしょうか？
One advantage of having this is
これを持つことの利点の 1 つは、
Because it is more colorful
よりカラフルになるので、
So everyone prefers to color like this
だから誰もがこのような色を好む
showy things add to us
派手なものは私たちに付加価値を与える
in our daily use
私たちの日常的な使用において
Because the colors that appear in this way
こうやって現れる色だから
will be brighter and brighter
ますます明るくなります
Our race likes to look at that beautiful thing
私たちの種族はその美しいものを見るのが好きです
strong color
強い色
It means very beautiful
とても美しいという意味です
Including this of our female compatriots
私たちの同胞である女性たちも含めて
Facial makeup also includes the use of various paints
顔のメイクにはさまざまな絵の具の使用も含まれます
Because there are all kinds of colors
いろんな色があるから
In the early days, put these paints like this
初期の頃はこんな感じで塗装してました
Like painting, it contains these heavy metals
絵画と同じように、これらの重金属が含まれています
Everyone knows that metals are not very healthy for the human body.
金属が人体にあまり良くないことは誰もが知っています。
So now these cosmetics
さて、今回の化粧品は
It has largely discarded these heavy metal-containing paints
これらの重金属を含む塗料はほとんど廃棄されています
Instead, organic substances are used as the color ingredients in cosmetics.
その代わりに化粧品の着色成分として有機物が使われています。
Well, this is me talking about modern times in one breath, right?
さて、これが私が一気に話した現代ですよね？
But you have to think about it
しかし、それについて考えなければなりません
These things are all because of chemical synthesis
これらはすべて化学合成によるものです
These various organic substances are produced
これらのさまざまな有機物が生成されます。
Organic matter is in fact basically
有機物は実は基本的に
The colors of these organic substances seen now
今見えるこの有機物の色
Of course it was synthesized in the laboratory.
もちろん実験室で合成されたものです。
or synthesized by the industry
または業界によって合成された
Early organic matter was also
初期の有機物にも
But we can see it but we can't use it
でも、見えるけど使えない
Because these early organic substances were roughly drawn from
なぜなら、これらの初期の有機物質は大まかに次のものから抽出されたからです。
For example, flowers show very bright colors
たとえば、花は非常に明るい色を示します。
What about the colors in the flowers?
花の色はどうでしょうか？
are also composed of these organic substances
もこれらの有機物質で構成されています
But whether these substances are the color of flowers
でもこれらの物質が花の色なのかどうか
or the color inside an animal's feathers
または動物の羽の内側の色
you can find a way to extract it
それを抽出する方法を見つけることができます
But these substances are not stable enough
しかし、これらの物質は十分に安定ではありません
Not long after you worked so hard to extract it
苦労して抽出してから間もなく
their color fades
彼らの色は褪せていく
So early these brightly colored substances
つまり、これらの初期の明るい色の物質は、
It took a lot of effort to get
入手するのに大変な努力が必要でした
I went to find a piece of information here.
ここで情報を探しに行きました。
It was the early days, which should have been in the Middle Ages.
それは中世であるはずの初期の頃でした。
flowers of the color of that time
あの時の色の花
It is still difficult to obtain
まだまだ入手困難です
At that time, there was a color called Taizi's dye
当時、太子の染料という色がありました
This Taizi is translated from the English name
この太子は英語名を翻訳したものです。
How did this dye get it?
この染料はどうやって手に入れたのでしょうか？
I learn a lot of English writing here
ここでたくさんの英作文を学びます
Let me translate for you
翻訳させてください
It's near the Mediterranean Sea and there's a man called Flying Mudbot
地中海の近くにフライング・マッドボットと呼ばれる男がいる
The Mudbots live next to the Mediterranean Sea
マッドボットは地中海の隣に住んでいます
There is a type of crustacean in that region of the Mediterranean Sea
地中海のその地域には一種の甲殻類がいます
This is what the crustacean inside it looks like
中の甲殻類はこんな感じです
You can find photos on the Internet
インターネット上で写真を見つけることができます
There is something in this color
この色には何かあります
When you extract it, it takes on this purple color
抽出するとこの紫色になります
So in the middle ages
それで中世には
to get this color
この色を手に入れるために
Because what was the color actually used for later?
なぜなら、その色は後で実際に何に使われたのか？
That this is the Pope's holy robe
これが教皇の聖衣だということ
You see this is a very famous portrait of Christianity
これはキリスト教の非常に有名な肖像画です
the angel inside
中の天使
this is still
これはまだです
jesus doesn't know what
イエスは何を知りませんか
The robe it wears is the prince
着ているローブは王子様
The color dyed by this dye
この染料で染めた色は
But the dye didn’t exist at that time, and the chemical solution didn’t come out yet.
でも当時は染料も存在せず、薬液もまだ出ていませんでした。
How does this person synthesize these organic dyes?
この人はどうやってこれらの有機染料を合成しているのでしょうか？
It's from this crustacean to extract it
この甲殻類から抽出するのです
Here's a narrative I'm talking about
これが私が話している物語です
you want to dye a dress like this
こんなドレスを染めたいの？
do you know how many shells this crustacean needs
この甲殻類に必要な貝殻の数を知っていますか
He said he wanted 10,000,000,100,000,12,000 of these crustaceans
彼は、これらの甲殻類を 10,000,000、100,000、12,000 個欲しいと言った
To be able to dye this piece of clothing
この服を染めることができるなんて
So you can know how difficult it is to obtain this pigment
この顔料を入手することがいかに難しいかがわかります。
So at that time in the Middle Ages
つまり、中世の当時、
Pigments are very, very difficult to obtain
顔料を入手するのは非常に困難です
So if you can have a color like this color
この色のような色があれば
Usually a symbol of some kind of power
通常、ある種の力の象徴
Those who are not expensive can afford it
お金が高くない人は買えますよ
can afford this color
この色の余裕はあります
this is
これは
is a history that you can look up
調べられる履歴です
Before artificially synthesizing these dyes
これらの染料を人工的に合成する前に
Acquiring dyes is quite a difficult thing
染料の入手はかなり難しい
We often hear people say
人々がこう言うのをよく聞きます。
What kind of tree roots are you going to extract from?
どのような木の根から抽出するのでしょうか？
This has a ready-made example
これには既製の例があります
This is called fenugreek root
これをフェヌグリークの根といいます
What color is the root of the chickweed
ハコベの根は何色ですか
brick red color
レンガの赤い色
Because there is one like this in it
中にはこんなのもあるから
The substance of the organic dye appears
有機染料の物質が現れる
So you use the extraction method
そこで、抽出方法を使用します
from a tree root like this
こんな木の根元から
Extract the substance of such a color
そのような色の物質を抽出する
so you can know
それであなたは知ることができます
The color is not fetched from
色は取得されません
All cancel a natural world
全てが自然界を打ち消してしまう
like canceling a fake shellfish
偽物の貝をキャンセルするようなもの
Otherwise, this is extracted from the root of the tree.
それ以外の場合、これはツリーのルートから抽出されます。
it's a hard job
それは大変な仕事です
The current situation like this
現状はこんな感じ
Until about 100 years ago
100年くらい前までは
Of course the one 150 years ago
もちろん150年前の物です
We now call him the emergence of Chemist
私たちは今、彼を「化学者の出現」と呼んでいます。
This situation has taken a big turn
この状況は大きく変わりました
We now respectfully call it chemical production
私たちは今、敬意を込めてそれを化学生産と呼んでいます
it's british called william burkey
ウィリアム・バーキーというイギリス人です
It existed from 1838 to 1907
1838 年から 1907 年まで存在しました
Probably around the end of the last century to the beginning of the last century
おそらく前世紀末から前世紀初頭頃
It's in fact the first human to synthesize it in a laboratory way
実際、実験室でそれを合成した最初の人類です
And inventing and synthesizing a substance with a new color appears
そして新しい色の物質を発明・合成することが登場します
This new color material is called intrinsically safe paper
この新しい色素材は本質安全防爆紙と呼ばれています
The color itself has this tinge of purple
色自体は紫っぽいです
light purple substance
薄紫色の物質
We call this chemical synthesis
これを化学合成と呼びます
Created the first entirely new organic dye
初の全く新しい有機染料を開発
This thing does not exist in nature
こんなものは自然界には存在しない
something like this structure
この構造のようなもの
and no such thing appears
そしてそのようなものは表示されません
So the thing it synthesizes is colored
つまり、合成したものには色が付きます
And it's a roughly non-existent color
そしてそれはほぼ存在しない色です
So it's a color created by humans
つまり人間が作り出した色なのです
matter of color
色の問題
This is what I found in a book
本で見つけたのがこれです
This is the internal substance that was synthesized in his laboratory at the beginning.
これは最初に彼の研究室で合成された内部物質です。
still preserved
まだ保存されています
This color is called book
この色はブックと呼ばれます
Yasuko Moto
本安子
This is what we now call the father of painters
この人は今では画家の父と呼ばれています
because you went to see his hometown
あなたが彼の故郷に会いに行ったから
His hometown has been turned into a museum
彼の故郷は博物館になった
there is a sign on it
そこに標識があります
If you zoom in to see him, look at him
彼を見るためにズームインしたら、彼を見てください
this person is actually
この人は実は
because he discovered the synthesis of this dye
彼はこの染料の合成を発見したからです
One of the next things he did was
次に彼がしたことの一つは、
He founded an industry based on scientific registration
彼は科学的登録に基づいた産業を設立しました
The meaning of this English word translated into Chinese
この英語の単語の意味を中国語に翻訳すると、
Science-based industry industry
科学に基づいた産業
means industry
産業を意味します
Industry didn't exist before him
彼の前には産業は存在しなかった
The painting industry we are talking about now
今話している塗装業界
just start with it
それから始めてください
what great things does it do
それはどんな素晴らしいことをするのですか
It is the self-preparation of the dye
染料のセルフ仕込みです
Produce in large quantities Collect in large quantities
大量に生産する 大量に収集する
Then take it to the market to sell
その後、市場に持ち込んで販売します
what color
何色
Because the package is very similar to the purple we talked about earlier.
というのも、パッケージが先ほどの紫によく似ているからです。
So it's purple when we talked about it
それで、私たちがそれについて話したとき、それは紫でした
This is extracted from the carapace and very hard work
これは甲羅から取り出すのですが、とても手間がかかります。
You have to collect tens of thousands of things to be able to dye a little cloth
少しの布を染めるためには何万ものものを集めなければなりません
Now it can be mass-produced at one time by synthetic means
今では合成手段で一度に大量生産できるようになりました
So the one with the color is no longer the rich and powerful
つまり、色を持つものはもはや豊かで強力なものではありません
It's something exclusive
それは何か排他的なものです
So here you see this is a book
これが本です
it says
それは言う
a man it invented a color
それが色を発明した男
And it's like this, this, this move
そして、それはこのように、この、この動きです
changed the whole world
全世界を変えた
I translated it into Chinese
中国語に翻訳してみました
a man invents a color
人は色を発明する
The world has changed since then
それ以来世界は変わりました
Thus began the chemical industry
こうして化学産業が始まりました
that's because
それは
From the beginning of it we will call it the father of chemical engineering
その始まりから私たちはそれを化学工学の父と呼ぶことにします
This is also a dye that it synthesized later.
これも後から合成した染料です。
This dye is Qiansu
この染料はQiansuです
is what we just saw earlier
それは先ほど見たばかりです
This thing extracted from the root of the tree
木の根元から取り出したものです
identical chemical structure
同一の化学構造
This is from the root of the tree
これは木の根元から
extracted from natural
天然から抽出された
This microlink thin product from the laboratory
研究室からのこのマイクロリンク薄型製品
Prepare it by chemical synthesis
自分で化学合成して作る
So this is so here you look up the history book
それで、ここで歴史の本を調べてください
It is written that this substance is
この物質はこう書いてある
produced by chemical synthesis
化学合成によって作られる
The first natural organic dye
初めての天然有機染料
This dye is found in nature
この染料は自然界に存在します
But in the past, it was extracted from the roots of trees.
しかし、昔は木の根から抽出されていました。
But it is synthesized by the laboratory
でもそれは研究室で合成されたものです
And another of its inventions is
そして、その発明のもう一つは、
There is no such thing in nature
自然界にはそんなものは存在しない
completely pure matter created in the laboratory
実験室で作られた完全に純粋な物質
Okay, let me tell you this is simple
わかりました、これは簡単なことですので教えてください
this is chemistry
これは化学です
How did Winter Night synthesize this dye?
Winter Night はどのようにしてこの染料を合成したのでしょうか?
add these three things together
これら 3 つを足し合わせます
All three are made of organic matter
3つはすべて有機物でできています
After putting these three things together
この３つを組み合わせると
Add running acid water and heavy acid
流酸水と重酸を加える
This acts as an oxidizing agent
これは酸化剤として働きます
You can put these three things in this ring together to fix it together
このリングの中にこの3つを入れて固定することができます
When Wenyuan International synthesized this thing
文源国際がこれを合成したとき
In fact it doesn't know
実際にはそれは分かりません
it gets in fact a mixture
実際には混合物になります
It includes ABCD
ABCDが含まれます
There are at least two ingredients of all sorts
あらゆる種類の材料が少なくとも 2 つあります
like this one I drew earlier
前に描いたこれと同じように
At least two ingredients make up its pot of medicine
少なくとも 2 つの成分が薬のポットを構成します
chemical
化学
this is colored
これは色が付いています
In fact the dye is not a single substance
実際、染料は単一の物質ではありません
In fact this mixture
実はこの混合物
It does this thing in fact it is not its original purpose
実はこれは本来の目的ではありません
write one here
ここに一つ書いてください
What was it actually supposed to do?
実際には何をするはずだったのでしょうか？
Back then that sadism was troublesome
あの頃はサディズムが面倒だった
At that time there was no medicine to treat
当時は治療する薬がなかった
I knew at that time
あの時知ってた
It is said that treating internal diseases can relieve the symptoms
内臓疾患を治療すると症状が軽減されると言われています
It is from this natural thing called
それはこの自然のものから来ています。
The bark or roots of economical numbers
経済的な数字の樹皮または根
It can be distilled into a thing called the neighbor
それを蒸留すると、隣人と呼ばれるものになります
It can be used to treat internal diseases
内臓疾患の治療にも使えます
Its original purpose at that time was to find a way
当時の本来の目的は方法を見つけることでした
This natural substance was synthesized in the laboratory
この天然物質は実験室で合成されました
You can see back then because chemistry was just out
化学が世に出たばかりだったので、当時のことがわかります
We're not that familiar with this synthesis yet.
私たちはまだこの合成にあまり慣れていません。
Everyone probably knows about this structure that there is a ring in it.
この構造の中にリングがあることは、おそらく誰もが知っているでしょう。
there are eggs in it
中に卵が入っています
There are some oxygen elements in it
酸素元素が多少含まれています
So it starts doing the poor job
それでそれはひどい仕事をし始めます
At that time, the source it chose was to choose these three things
その時に選んだソースはこの3つでした
to group it and put those groups
それをグループ化してそれらのグループを配置します
hope to get this thing
これを手に入れることを願っています
Of course it is impossible
もちろん無理です
We know chemistry very well now
私たちは今では化学をよく知っています
It's impossible to get this thing like this
これをこのように手に入れるのは不可能です
So its original purpose was not to be a dye
つまり、本来の目的は染料ではなかったのです
It's actually purely for medical purposes
実は純粋に医療目的なんです
synthetic work in education
教育における総合的な取り組み
And the narrow false found that it got a colored substance
そして、狭い偽者は、色のついた物質を手に入れたことを発見しました
You see it in a beaker with a jar of purple ejaculation in it
ビーカーの中に紫色の射精が入った瓶が入っているのが見えるだろう
is a drawing
絵です
It means that it was walking around in the laboratory at that time
その時研究室の中を歩き回っていたということです
In the end, I got a medicine that I didn't get, but I got a colored substance
結局手に入らなかった薬を手に入れましたが、色のついた物を手に入れました
its brain moves fast
その脳は速く動く
It wants to say that this is very similar to Taier Paper
これは Taier Paper に非常に似ていると言いたいのです
So it can be sold on the market
だから市場でも売れるんだよ
So it actually retired very early
つまり、実際には非常に早く引退しました
It retired in its 30s
30代で引退した
because it invented the dye in the 20s
20年代に染料を発明したからです
big money ever since
それ以来大金
it just keeps working
それはただ働き続けます
it's at home by itself
それはそれ自体で家にあります
It has set up a laboratory at home
自宅に研究室を設置しました
I am researching and developing various dyes by myself
独自で様々な染料を研究開発しています
Because at that time around 30 years old it had already made enough money
当時30歳くらいでもう十分稼げてたから
Just retreat into the rivers and lakes and do research at home
川や湖にこもって、家で研究をするだけです
this and more
これとそれ以上
this is chemical
これは化学物質です
Just now I said that he artificially synthesized the first natural dye
先ほど、彼は最初の天然染料を人工的に合成したと言いました
He started with this substance
彼はこの物質から始めました
This substance is extracted from plum oil
この物質は梅油から抽出されます。
After one step, two steps and three steps you will get this
1 ステップ、2 ステップ、3 ステップを経ると、次の結果が得られます。
Appearance of chigusa reddish yellow dye
千草赤黃色的染料出現
The Chicasana yellow dye was made to the UK
チカサナイエローの染料はイギリスで製造されました
Because that Poke-Voyance Brit
だってあのポケボヤンスブリット
This early British floating oath has this red uniform on it
この初期の英国の浮遊宣誓にはこの赤いユニフォームが付いています
This is the dye used for dyeing
染色に使用する染料です
Well, there is another thing that is related to the material of that Thai son.
さて、そのタイ人の息子のネタに関連してもう一つあります。
A very similar thing is called Indigo dye
非常によく似たものはインディゴ染料と呼ばれます
Indigo dye we now translate it as called
現在ではインディゴ染料と訳されています。
what is this called
これは何と呼ばれていますか
electric blue dye
エレクトリックブルー染料
Indigo dye
藍染め
This thing is actually what we use to dye jeans now
実はこれ、今ジーンズを染めるのに使っているんです
What about the blue pigment dye that is used the most?
最もよく使われる青色の顔料染料はどうでしょうか？
this is the thing
これが問題です
This stuff is actually the same dye as Tay's son
これは実際にはテイの息子と同じ染料です
The results of non-resembling
非類似の結果
The fetus is in these two positions
胎児はこの 2 つの位置にあります
In two more show elements
さらに 2 つのショー要素で
You take these two show elements
2 つのショー要素を取り込みます
after removing it
それを取り外した後
closer to blue
青に近い
What about the blue pigment?
青色の色素はどうでしょうか？
In fact, as we said earlier
実際、先ほども述べたように、
you want to get from that crustacean
あなたはその甲殻類から得たいです
Distilling this non-functional and hard work
この非機能的で大変な作業を抽出する
Otherwise you have to get it from the plant
それ以外の場合は工場から入手する必要があります
This plant is called
この植物はこう呼ばれます
Inside the plant of Miaolan
苗蘭工場内
This thing can also be extracted
こんなものも抽出できる
But this refinement is also very troublesome
しかし、この調整も非常に面倒です
to go through this
これを通過するために
Heavy extraction and purification steps
大量の抽出および精製ステップ
to get a little something
ちょっとしたものを手に入れるために
So the chemical industry in Germany is very fresh
ドイツの化学産業は非常に新鮮です
At that time, Germany's Basford Industries
当時、ドイツのバスフォード・インダストリーズ社は、
no it's not basford
いいえ、バスフォードではありません
this bell
この鐘
Bell is actually owned by Bayer AG in Germany.
実際、ベルはドイツのバイエル社が所有しています。
the founder
創設者
He is also the winner of the Nobel Prize in Chemistry
彼はノーベル化学賞の受賞者でもあります
He invented this synthetic method
彼はこの合成法を発明した
It's like Tyrian paper
ティリアンの紙みたいだ
color dye
色の染料
After these two steps, he can get
これら 2 つのステップを経て、次のことが得られます。
That was in 1882, over six years old
それは1882年、6年以上前のことでした
The era of unknown writers and artists
無名アーティストの時代
At that time, Germany's chemical industry also began to regenerate.
当時、ドイツの化学産業も再生を始めました。
This synthesis is inconvenient
この合成は不便です
improved later
後で改善されました
A synthetic christian improvement made by this guy
この男が作った合成キリスト教の改良版
from a less expensive precursor
より安価な前駆体から
It is easier to get this dye out
この染料を取り出すのが簡単です
This is later all changed to use
これは後ですべて使用するように変更されます
Lugong Chemical Synthesis
鹿公化学合成
Because the chemical synthesis of Lun Gong is much better than the extraction from natural substances
ルンゴンの化学合成は天然物質からの抽出よりもはるかに優れているため
Or it's much more convenient to extract from the inside of that crustacean
あるいは、その甲殻類の内部から抽出する方がはるかに便利です
The price is cheap, it can be much cheaper
価格は安いので、もっと安くなる可能性があります
Anyone who has entered the era of the chemical industry
化学産業の時代に入った人
This dye was invented after such a twists and turns
紆余曲折を経てこの染料が発明されました
Then we use the most truthful product now
それから、私たちは今、最も誠実な製品を使用しています
It's a plastic product
プラスチック製品です
Everyone knows that plastic products are often colorless.
プラスチック製品は無色の場合が多いことは誰もが知っています。
But like the clothes you physically wear
でも、あなたが物理的に着る服のように
These are all made of the real fiber of the real product
これらはすべて実際の製品の本物の繊維で作られています
It was all colorless
全部無色だった
why now we can wear
なぜ今着られるのか
There are so many colors
とてもたくさんの色があります
because of all the plastic inside
内部はすべてプラスチックなので
The dye of ginseng is in this
高麗人参の染料はこれに入っています
plastic we can see this
プラスチック、これを見ることができます
Whether it is PVC, PS
PVCかPSか
Di density, drama language, high-density drama language and
ディ密度、ドラマ情報、高密度ドラマ情報、
The drama interest and that PET
ドラマの面白さとあのPET
The material of the PET bottle is called PET.
ペットボトルの素材はPETと呼ばれます。
There will be colors in it
そこには色が入ります
The color without ginseng is like this
高麗人参なしの色はこんな感じ
is white or transparent
白または透明です
this is its original color
これが本来の色です
But you see these new doctors in every color
しかし、あなたはこれらの新しい医師があらゆる色を持っているのを見ます
All with added dyes or pigments
すべて染料または顔料が添加されています
Only after going inside will these colors appear
中に入って初めてこの色が現れる
Otherwise our world would be very dull
そうでなければ私たちの世界はとても退屈になってしまうでしょう
either white or black
白か黒のどちらか
Without the invention of this dye
この染料の発明がなければ
This is about a thing that was often published in newspapers a while ago
少し前によく新聞に載っていた内容です
peer ratio
ピア比率
This thing is it's a natural pigment
これは天然色素です
It's a natural pigment very close to something
何かに近い天然色素です
The closest natural pigment to it is the leaf green tree
これに最も近い天然色素は葉緑樹です
we know the natural world
私たちは自然界を知っています
you look at the leaves of that tree
あなたはその木の葉を見ます
That is, each color of multicolored ice has its own color.
つまり、多色の氷の各色は独自の色を持っています。
The green in it is made of this
中の緑はこれでできています
This is a natural substance
これは天然物質です
That's where the chemical structure of the chlorophyll tree is located
そこにクロロフィルの木の化学構造があります。
Look at this sodium copper chlorophyllin
このナトリウム銅クロロフィリンを見てください
Does it look very similar to this structure?
この構造によく似ていますか？
It removes the long tail
長い尻尾を取り除きます
then it puts
それからそれは置きます
I see this upside down
これを逆さまに見ると
Everything else looks very similar
他はすべて非常によく似ています
There is one thing that is different
違うことが1つあります
It puts the beautiful element of MG in the middle
MGの美しい要素を真ん中に置きます
changed to copper
銅に変わりました
why is this thing called copper
なぜこれが銅と呼ばれるのか
The reason this word is in it
この言葉が入っている理由
It is because it puts the beauty in the leafy green tree
それは、緑豊かな木本来の美しさをそのままにしているからです。
The metal was replaced by copper
金属は銅に置き換えられました
and then it's next to this
そして、この隣にあります
this is a sour root
これは酸っぱい根です
The acid radical will carry an ion with a that
酸ラジカルはイオンを運びます。
in this position with
この位置で
All three positions will carry acid radicals
3 つの位置すべてが酸ラジカルを保持します
and then carry that
そしてそれを持ち歩きます
so this position
それでこの位置
The name of this painting is called Same Ye Filter Tree Na
この絵の名前はSame Ye Filter Tree Naといいます。
I found this from the website
ウェブサイトからこれを見つけました
I'll read it for everyone
みんなに読んであげます
Although everyone understands what it means
誰もがその意味を理解しているにもかかわらず、
The same leaf filter refers to the leaf filter semi-synthetic
同じリーフフィルターは、半合成リーフフィルターを指します。
a practical pigment
実用的な顔料
it's actually edible
それは実際に食べられる
it is called natural green tree
それは天然の緑の木と呼ばれます
number three
数3
It also has an English serial number called 1141
1141という英語のシリアル番号も付いています。
In Taiwan, it is a practical pigment that can be added at zero clock
台湾ではゼロクロックで添加できる実用的な顔料です
But it cannot be added to the practical oil
ただし実用油には添加できません
A while ago, the inner defender in the newspaper made a shameful mistake.
少し前に新聞に載ったインサイドディフェンダーが恥ずかしいミスをした。
it adds it to utility oil
ユーティリティオイルに添加します
this is not allowed
これは許可されていません
it's illegal
それは違法です
it is edible
それは食べられる
But it cannot be added to utility oil
ただし、汎用油には添加できません
The leaf filter tree we just saw in nature
先ほど自然の中で見た濾過木
The leaf filter tree is a plant that has
濾過木は次のような植物です。
A source of many pigments
多くの色素の供給源
The other is that compared to plants, they are animals
もう一つは、植物と比較すると動物であるということです。
what about animals
動物はどうですか
is red because blood is red
赤いのは血が赤いから
that makes these two very different colors
それにより、この 2 つの色はまったく異なります
In fact, its chemistry is very similar
実際、その化学的性質は非常に似ています
The following is the main structure of the leaf green tree
以下はリーフグリーンツリーの主な構造です。
The one above is our red blood cell
上にあるのは赤血球です
Iron fingers in red blood cells
赤血球の鉄の指
Red blood cells should, in fact, also be colorless
赤血球も実際には無色のはずです
But it contains a thing like this
でも中にはこんなものが入ってます
This thing is available in red color
このものは赤色で利用可能です
Do you see that this structure looks very similar to
この構造が次のものと非常によく似ていることがわかりますか?
Except for the middle this is a beauty
真ん中以外は美品です
above is an iron
上はアイロンです
different metal
異なる金属
The structure of Zhongwei is also slightly different
中衛の構造も少し異なります
But the color is so different
でも色が違いすぎる
one is red one is green
1つは赤、もう1つは緑です
This is a newspaper from two or three years ago
これは２、３年前の新聞です
I don't know if you guys still remember
皆さんがまだ覚えているかどうかはわかりませんが、
Looking at the body, it means that there is a daughter-in-law who wants to kill his in-laws
遺体を見ると義理の両親を殺そうとする嫁がいるということになる
what did he put in it
彼はそれに何を入れましたか
He put a pinch of sour in their meal
彼は彼らの食事にサワーをひとつまみ入れた
What is subsoleic acid?
サブソレイン酸とは何ですか?
It's the bacon thing
それはベーコンの事です
Sodium nitrite chemical molecule is NANO2
亜硝酸ナトリウムの化学分子は NANO2 です
It's the combination of Assiolic Acid and
それはアジオル酸と
Assona
アソナ
This thing is actually an oxidizing agent
実はこれ、酸化剤なんです
it will eat into the human body
それは人間の体を蝕みます
It will take the ferrous iron in the heme
ヘムに含まれる第一鉄を摂取します
the action of oxidation
酸化の作用
Turn Iron Two into Iron Three
アイアン 2 をアイアン 3 に変える
Our human blood must be able to absorb oxygen
私たち人間の血液は酸素を吸収できなければなりません
We need oxygen to breathe
私たちが呼吸するには酸素が必要です
Rely on the second iron frame
2本目の鉄枠に頼る
Once the iron two frame is replaced by the iron three frame
鉄二枠が鉄三枠に置き換わったら
Human blood can no longer absorb oxygen
人間の血液は酸素を吸収できなくなります
so people die
だから人は死ぬ
What are your symptoms?
あなたの症状は何ですか?
Normal blood looks red
正常な血液は赤く見える
But that's because of the iron content of Iron II
しかし、それは鉄Ⅱの鉄分によるものです。
But if you turn Iron II into Iron III
しかし、Iron II を Iron III にすると、
What about iron quality at this time?
この時の鉄の品質はどうでしょうか？
It looks darker
暗く見えます
Look at the left and right hands
左手と右手を見てください
It's the color of the hands of the poisoned in-laws
それは毒を盛られた義理の両親の手の色だ
because its blood can no longer absorb oxygen
血液が酸素を吸収できなくなるからです
At that time the report said
当時の報告書にはこう書かれていた
It was later discovered that it was because of the poison
後に毒が原因だったことが判明
they are in the hospital
彼らは病院にいる
Symptoms of a poisoning like this
中毒の症状はこんな感じ
can add this sub
このサブを追加できます
First
甲
blue
藍
this thing
このこと
In fact this is a finite color substance
実際、これは有限色の物質です
This thing can help put this iron shirt rack
これはこのアイアンシャツラックを置くのに役立ちます
Revert back to Iron Erjia
アイアンエルジアに戻す
In fact, what about this colored substance?
実際、この色の物質はどうなるのでしょうか？
also a potion
ポーションも
In fact it can do that oxidative mixing action
実際、酸化的混合作用を行うことができます。
itself it is blue
それ自体は青いです
you can see it melt in the water
水に溶けるのがわかります
There is a blue substance in the water
水の中に青い物質がある
you go
あなたが行く
If you have to look it up
調べる必要がある場合
you can see it's a chemical indicator
化学指標であることがわかります
Also a dye
染料でもある
because it has a color relationship
色の関係があるので
It is also a biological stain
これも生物汚れです
you can see this above
これは上で見ることができます
The word is the tissue of the human body
言葉は人体の組織です
After applying this dye
この染料を塗った後
You can see it renders this blue
これが青色にレンダリングされるのがわかります
presented
提示された
So this release is also a dye thing
なので今回のリリースも染料のものです
Because as long as there is color, we can call it a dye
色さえあれば染料と言えるから
And the dye is actually an antidote
そしてその染料は実は解毒剤なのです
Once you plant this acesena poison
このアセセナ毒を植えたら
Just rely on this to detoxify
これに頼るだけでデトックスできる
This news report is headline news
この報道はヘッドラインニュースです
There are several chemicals in it
いくつかの化学物質が入っている
includes this dye
この染料が含まれています
This bacon is included
このベーコンが入っています
In fact, this is our pool of people
実際、これが私たちの人材プールです
this will be poisonous
これは毒になります
with this leafy green tree or ferrite
この緑豊かな木やフェライトで
a very similar thing
非常によく似たもの
It's a synthetic thing
合成の物ですよ
This is a thing that is used a lot in the industry
業界ではよく使われているものです
Because this is completely produced by synthesis in the laboratory
完全に実験室で合成して作られているため、
These things are also dyes or pigments
これらも染料または顔料です
Dye called Taiqinglin
太清銀という染料
Or I can see it in
または、私はそれを見ることができます
It's very similar to the ferrous structure
鉄の構造によく似ています
just in the four corners
ちょうど四隅にある
Change this CH to N
このCHをNに変更します
changed to bomb
爆弾に変わった
The structure of Yuanyuan's large plate still looks exactly the same
袁園の大皿の構造は今も全く同じに見える
But this color is just like these four eggs
でもこの色はこの4つの卵と同じです
It's not the same as without these four colors
この4色が無いのと同じじゃないですか
Originally, the inside of the iron paper was red.
もともと鉄紙の内側は赤かったのです。
If it were changed to beauty, it might be green
美しさに変えるなら緑かも
This one has four more eggs and then replaced it with a bucket
これにはさらに卵が4個あり、それをバケツに置き換えました
or no bucket
またはバケツがない
The color itself is blue
色自体は青です
like this is very blue blue
これはとても青いです
or so this one is bluish
というかこれは青っぽいです
This type of substance is a pigment dye that is completely functionally synthesized.
この種の物質は完全に機能的に合成された顔料染料です。
This thing is much more stable than iron paper or these
これは鉄紙やこれらよりもはるかに安定しています
Such dyes and pigments are widely used in some optoelectronic industries
このような染料や顔料は、一部のオプトエレクトロニクス産業で広く使用されています。
Let's come back to the photoelectric application later.
光電応用については後で戻りましょう。
Next, let's talk about the substance of this color.
次にこの色の正体についてお話します
is about this practical pigment
この実用的な顔料についてです
As we mentioned earlier, Tongye Suna
先ほどもお話しましたが、トンイェ・ソナ
That is allowed to be added to the utility
実用的な製品に追加することが許可されている
But it cannot be added to utility oil
ただし、汎用油には添加できません
that too
それも
is a food coloring
食品着色料です
there are many things
多くのものがあります
inside what we eat
私たちが食べるものの中に
In order to increase the vividness of the food
食材の鮮やかさを増すために
Usually some coloring is added here
通常、ここに色が追加されます
What is allowed to be added is called
追加が許可されているものは次のように呼ばれます
Qualified edible artificial coloring
認定された食用人工着色料
These edible artificial colors
これらの食用人工着色料は、
Let me give you an example
例を挙げてみましょう
I didn't know you liked this hot dog
あなたがこのホットドッグが好きだとは知りませんでした
This is a very standard hot dog thing
これは非常に標準的なホットドッグです
hot dog with bun
パン付きホットドッグ
there is a sausage in it
中にソーセージが入っています
Then usually put this ketchup and mustard sauce
そして通常はこのケチャップとマスタードソースを入れます
Food coloring is added to mustard, ketchup, and hot dogs
マスタード、ケチャップ、ホットドッグには食品着色料が添加されています
Because otherwise the colors wouldn't be so bright
そうしないと色がこんなに明るくならないから
ketchup is red, right?
ケチャップって赤いですよね？
Added this orange-red pigment in it
このオレンジがかった赤色の顔料を加えました
What about the yellow mustard?
黄色いマスタードはどうでしょうか？
Added this yellow pigment inside
中にこの黄色の顔料を加えました
There is also this orange-red pigment added to the sausage
ソーセージにはこのオレンジがかった赤色の色素も添加されています
These three pigments are classified according to their chemical structure
これら 3 つの顔料は、化学構造に従って分類されます。
All three are called
3つとも呼ばれます
Mouth Tears Dye
口の涙の染料
colorful
カラフル
one is orange
一つはオレンジです
one is yellow
一つは黄色です
add to this
これに追加します
Can make your hot fruit look more salivating
ホットフルーツの唾液をより分泌させることができます
The color is very strong and very bright
色がとても強くてとても明るいです
whet your appetite
食欲をそそる
something like this
このようなもの
are also widely used on these planet-colored
これらの惑星でも広く使用されています
inside the food
食べ物の中
Like this is MMM's chocolate candy
これはMMMのチョコレートキャンディーです
This is Regan's candy
これはリーガンのキャンディーです
Called Jerry Bean
ジェリー・ビーンと呼ばれる
There are many different colors in the edible drink
食べ物の飲み物にはさまざまな色があります
Wind model with pills
錠剤を使用した風モデル
It is usually colored inside
通常は内側に色が付いています
These edible artificial colors are usually added
これらの食用人工着色料は通常添加されます
I remember this one is called Marco Dirty
これはマルコ・ダーティという名前だったと記憶しています
See various colors inside
内部のさまざまな色をご覧ください
It's all food coloring.
全て食用色素です。
You can easily find it online
ネットで簡単に探せますよ
What are these food colorings?
これらの食品着色料は何ですか?
these things
これらの事
The ones listed above are the pigments of silver Xu in the United States
上記のものは米国の銀徐の顔料です。
Different countries have different banking licenses
国が違えば銀行ライセンスも異なります
Using the United States as the standard, these chemical structures I have found out
アメリカを基準として私が調べた化学構造
It's all organic chemicals and they're colored
すべて有機化学物質で着色されています
Some may be blue, some may be red, yellow, orange
青のものもあれば、赤、黄、オレンジのものもある
These are allowed to be added to the utility
これらはユーティリティへの追加が許可されています
substances that add color
色を加える物質
There are also some pigments that come from nature
自然由来の色素もあります
For example, astaxanthin
例えばアスタキサンチン
In fact you can in the pharmaceutical factory
実は製薬工場でもできるんです
You can get this at the pharmacy
これは薬局で買えます
it's not a drug it's a drug called like a vitamin
それは薬ではありません、ビタミンのような名前の薬です
is a tonic thing
強壮剤です
It's sold inside, you can see what's inside this orange-red capsule
中で販売されています。このオレンジがかった赤いカプセルの中に何が入っているかを見ることができます
liquid is astaxanthin
液体はアスタキサンチン
it puts it in oil
それを油の中に入れます
itself it is cloth body like this one
それ自体はこのような布ボディです
very dark orange-red colored powder
非常に濃いオレンジがかった赤色の粉末
It is also an organic substance
それも有機物質です
lots of doubles in it
ダブルがたくさん入ってる
Here are 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 は次のとおりです。
eleven, twelve, thirteen
十十一、十二、十三
From head to tail, fourteen or fifteen double swords
頭から尻尾まで、双剣が十四、五本
So the wavelength of its color can be extended to
したがって、その色の波長は次のように拡張できます。
within this range of long-wavelength red
この範囲の長波長赤色
This thing actually takes tea from nature
これは実際に自然からお茶を採取したものです
Much more convenient than artificial synthesis
人工合成より断然便利
I'll check it out
確かめます
Artificial, like this category, all substances that belong to this category are called
このカテゴリと同様に、このカテゴリに属する​​すべての物質は人工と呼ばれます。
family of carotenoid trees
カロテノイドの木の家族
What's Included Beta Carrot Tree
ベータ キャロット ツリー
yellow tree including corn leaves
トウモロコシの葉を含む黄色い木
What we saw before me looks like this
目の前に見えたのはこんな感じ
This is actually produced from the algae itself
これは実際には藻類そのものから生成されます
Obtain the pigment of the shrimp mangrove like this from this algae
この藻類からエビマングローブの色素をこんな感じで採取
Much simpler than synthetic
合成よりもはるかにシンプル
Because the synthesis is more troublesome
合成が面倒なので
so this thing especially this thing
だからこれ、特にこれ
We won't be so stupid as to say we synthesize it ourselves in the lab
研究室で自分たちで合成するなんて言うほど私たちは愚かではない
Because it will cost more to synthesize it yourself
自分で合成するとコストがかかるので
to do the synthetic work
合成作業を行う
this is
これは
It is some steps of artificial synthesis
人工合成のいくつかのステップです
you see very troublesome
とても面倒なことですね
many steps
多くのステップ
So it's better to go find that naturally
だからそれは自然に見つけたほうがいいよ
Looking for a class?
クラスをお探しですか?
The convenience of extracting from looking for classes
クラス検索から抽出できる便利さ
What about the same substance?
同じ物質ではどうでしょうか？
Also includes this nightshade tree and carrot tree
このナスの木とニンジンの木も含まれています
that yellow
あの黄色
orange-yellow substance
橙黄色の物質
All belong to this category
すべてこのカテゴリに属します
Substances of this family
このファミリーの物質
There is another kind of colored
他にも色違いがあります
These are the fruits we often eat
これらは私たちがよく食べる果物です
this dark fruit
この黒い果実
like blueberries or grapes
ブルーベリーやブドウのように
Eggplant Helizi
ナスのヘリジ
This is a dye that contains the same pigment
これは同じ色素を含む染料です
This is called a flower tree
これを花木といいます
These are usually reddish substances
これらの物質は通常赤みを帯びています
What about this flower tree?
この花木はどうでしょうか？
there is another thing
別のことがある
also often appear
もよく登場します
somewhat similar to that structure
その構造に少し似ています
called the color inside the hydrangea
アジサイの中の色と呼ばれる
hydrangea inside color
アジサイの内側の色
It also contains this anthocyanin tree
このアントシアニンの木も含まれています
The top of the structure of the anthocyanin tree
花青樹的結構上面
His color will follow the color of your soil
彼の色はあなたの土の色に従うでしょう
Variations in acidity and alkalinity
酸性とアルカリ性の変化
This is a substance that belongs to the color of nature
これは自然の色に属する物質です
ok this is his time
よし、今度は彼の時間だ
about ten minutes
約10分
In more than ten minutes, I took the second half of this
後半を10分以上にまとめました
finish it
それを終わらせて
I'm going to talk about it next
次にそれについて話します
These we have talked about so far are called
これまで説明してきたこれらは、
traditional dyeing and finishing process
伝統的な染色と仕上げのプロセス
The dyes we use are usually for coloring
私たちが使用する染料は通常、着色するために使用されます
make things come out in color
物事を色で浮かび上がらせる
This is a more traditional approach
これはより伝統的なアプローチです
What about the current technology?
現在のテクノロジーについてはどうですか？
actually go one step further
実際にはさらに一歩進んでいます
We're no longer talking about color
私たちはもう色のことについて話しているのではありません
We are using some of its photoelectric characteristics
その光電特性の一部を利用しています
same color
同じ色
but we're using it for this
しかし、私たちはこれをこのために使用しています
Inside the optoelectronic components
光電子部品の内部
TV-like color rendering
テレビのような色彩表現
The presentation of the color of the mobile phone panel
携帯電話パネルの色の表現
Also like what you see here
そしてここで見られるように
The discs we use to record data
データの記録に使用するディスク
These dyes are actually used in it.
実はこれらの染料が使われているんです。
This is more modern and not traditional
これは伝統的なものではなく、より現代的なものです
Let's talk about the traditional dyeing and printing process
伝統的な染色と捺染のプロセスについて話しましょう
Now it means that it is applied to optoelectronic technology
今では光電子技術への応用ということになります
Although this technology is a bit outdated
この技術は少し時代遅れではありますが、
But this was considered a very
しかし、これは非常に重要であると考えられていました
More than ten years ago, twenty years ago, it was considered a very popular new technology
10年以上前、20年前、それは非常に人気のある新技術とみなされていました
It is a technology for storing data
データを保存する技術です
It's the CD.
CDです。
In fact, there is a layer of dye in it.
実は中には染料の層が入っています。
Look at this English word, low crooked one means dye
この英語の単語を見てください、低く曲がったものは染料を意味します
In the middle it is a very thin multilayer film
真ん中は非常に薄い多層フィルムです
One of the layers is the substance of this dye
層の 1 つはこの染料の物質です
The reason why it can record is that this dye absorbs
なぜ記録できるのかというと、この色素が吸収するからです。
We need to use a laser light to do the action of burning the road
道路を燃やすにはレーザー光を使用する必要があります
it will absorb this laser light
このレーザー光を吸収します
And the dye in this place will go bad
そしてここの染料は悪くなってしまう
so need
だから必要です
Substances that receive laser light
レーザー光を受ける物質
Laser light is also a kind of light
レーザー光も光の一種です
a type of visible light
可視光線の一種
So this basically needs to rely on dyes
したがって、これは基本的に染料に依存する必要があります
In order to be able to achieve this application
このアプリケーションを実現できるようにするには
well everyone knows this
まあ誰もがこれを知っています
There are two types of discs
ディスクは2種類あります
One piece is 500Mbz
1枚は500Mbzです
For DVD2, it is several Gigabytes larger
DVD2 の場合は数ギガバイト大きくなります
The storage space varies in size
収納スペースはサイズによって異なります
depending on the dye used in it is not the same
使用されている染料によっては同じではありません
like the dye used in CD2
CD2で使用されている染料のように
Usually one of these three
通常はこの3つのうちのどれか
DVD2's dye is a fact
DVD2の染料は事実です
I can't argue with this information
この情報には異論はありません
Because this is a winter night secret
これは冬の夜の秘密だから
wait you will do
待ってください、あなたがします
I don't want to tell you what exactly it is used for
具体的に何に使われるかは言いたくない
we just know
私たちはただ知っています
It uses these two types of dyes
この2種類の染料を使用しています
Synin's Dye or Azol Metal Dye
Synin の染料またはアゾール金属染料
This Azol is what we saw earlier
このアゾールは先ほど見たものです
Yellow game dye to paint roads
道路を塗るための黄色のジビエ染料
is one of a kind
唯一無二です
That one is also called Azol Dye
それはアゾール染料とも呼ばれます
it just exists
それはただ存在するだけです
Hot dog, what, what?
ホットドッグ、何、何？
What about the color in ketchup and mustard?
ケチャップとマスタードの色はどうでしょうか？
It is also a kind of dichotic dye that belongs to the Azure band
また、Azure バンドに属する二分性染料の一種でもあります。
This Traner dye is also used in the production of this DVDR
この Traner 色素は、この DVDR の製造にも使用されています。
Next, this is really about optoelectronic technology.
次に、これは実際に光電子技術に関するものです。
The reason why our LCD screen can show color
液晶画面に色が見える理由
In fact, a thing called a color-producing green light film is used in it.
実はこれには発色グリーンライトフィルムというものが使われています。
This is a presentation of complementary colors
補色のご紹介です
The color-producing green film is to green out the color we don't want
色を生成する緑色のフィルムは、望まない色を緑色にします。
Then filter out the color we want to see
次に、見たい色をフィルターで除外します
This is a display of a complementary color that is a color that cancels out
それを打ち消す補色表示です。
This green light film needs to use some colored substances
この緑色光フィルムにはいくつかの着色物質を使用する必要があります
to absorb the colors we don't want
望まない色を吸収する
For example, the screen display usually has three colors: red, blue and green.
たとえば、画面表示には通常、赤、青、緑の 3 色があります。
So if you want to see red, you have to follow blue
だから、赤を見たいなら、青に従わなければなりません
remove the green ones
緑色のものを取り除きます
So for example like this is a green dye
たとえば、これは緑色の染料です
the reason it's green
緑色の理由
Because it absorbs red and blue
赤と青を吸収するので
so a green coloring or dye needs to be used in it
そのため、緑色の着色料または染料を使用する必要があります
this is its option
これはそのオプションです
In the current LCD technology
現在の液晶技術では
The green light film used in this
この作品で使われているグリーンライトフィルムは、
What about this green pigment?
この緑色の色素はどうでしょうか？
just use this thing
これを使ってください
This is what blue is used for
青はこんな用途に使われます
This is what we just saw
これが私たちが今見たものです
this thing
このこと
CUPC
CUPC
This is one that is produced in millions of metric tons per year
これは年間数百万トンで生産されるものです
A very useful coloring used in the craft world
クラフトの世界で使用される非常に便利なカラーリング
Because it appears blue or cyan color
青や水色に見えるので
This substance is very stable
この物質は非常に安定です
So it can be used on the green light film of this LCD
このLCDのグリーンライトフィルムに使用できます。
This is CUPC
これがCUPCです
the same substance
同じ物質
it's a
それは
a blue pigment
青い顔料
Red is made of such a substance
赤はこんな物質でできている
This substance is also used in the paint of the car
この物質は車の塗装にも使われています
orange red we saw that before
オレンジレッド、前にも見たよ
Maforomio's baking paint is also used by some companies
マフォロミオの焼付け塗料は一部の企業でも使用されています
painted on the top of the car
車の上部に塗装しました
Because these three pigments are very stable
これら 3 つの色素は非常に安定しているため、
It can be stored for a long time without deterioration
劣化せずに長期保存可能
Even under the light of LCE
LCEの光の下でも
it won't break
壊れないよ
Therefore, the reason why the LCD screen can present a variety of colors
したがって、液晶画面がさまざまな色を表現できる理由は次のとおりです。
With this color filter
このカラーフィルターを使うと
The color filter relies on these three pigments
カラーフィルターはこの3つの顔料で構成されています。
Red, blue and green pigments to filter out unwanted light colors
不要な光の色を除去する赤、青、緑の顔料
This way you can piece together a variety of
こうすることで色々な物を組み合わせることができます
colorful lin red color
カラフルなリンレッドカラー
good this
いいですね、これ
we've been talking so far
私たちはこれまで話してきました
Eliminate the application of models or complementary colors
モデルや補色の適用を排除する
Include this app in solar tv
このアプリをソーラーテレビに含めます
dyes are also used
染料も使われている
This dye also utilizes the erasing type
この染料も消去タイプを利用しています
Or the color of the complementary color appears
あるいは補色の色が現れる
we talked about it from the beginning
私たちは最初からそれについて話しました
things will show dye
物には染料が現れる
It's all caused by sunlight
すべては太陽光のせいだ
As long as a certain color of sunlight is absorbed
特定の色の太陽光が吸収される限り
This thing will show up in color
これは色で表示されます
The colors that appear are called complementary colors
現れる色を補色といいます
For example, as you see this is translucent
たとえば、ご覧のとおり、これは半透明です
inside these things
これらのものの中に
yellow like this one
このような黄色
That is, it absorbs the cyan color
つまり、シアン色を吸収します。
To show its complementary color is to show yellow
その補色を示すことは黄色を示すことです
able to appear red
赤く見えることができる
It is to absorb its protective color
保護色を吸収するためです
In this case, it will appear that what is left is the red color.
この場合、残っているのは赤色だけであるように見えます。
This is what we are currently doing research on
これは私たちが現在研究していることです
Various colors that are often used
よく使われる多彩なカラー
we are designing
私たちは設計しています
What color material can absorb sunlight
太陽光を吸収できる色の素材は何ですか
The more you absorb sunlight, the more you think about this effect.
太陽光を吸収すればするほど、この影響について考えることが多くなります。
The higher the efficiency of the panel it can battery
パネルの効率が高いほどバッテリーを充電できる
So this is a comparison
それでこれは比較です
The application of a technology that is still in the research stage
まだ研究段階にある技術の応用
good
良い
we just talked about so far
今まで話したばかりです
We're talking about what's called an evanescent color representation.
私たちが話しているのは、いわゆるエバネッセントカラー表現です。
is what we see is a complementary color
私たちが見ているのは補色です
Next, the last ten or so slides will talk about additive color
次に、最後の 10 枚ほどのスライドでは加法混色について説明します。
A phenomenon in which additive color is opposite to subtractive color
加法混色と減法混色が逆になる現象
if we want to see blue
もし私たちが青を見たいなら
We are the blue light
私たちは青い光です
that is blue
それは青です
Green light is green
緑の信号は緑です
Red light is red
赤信号は赤です
All three light colors play together
3 つの光の色すべてが一緒に再生されます
what is that
それは何ですか
just white
ただ白い
This is an additive color
これは加法混色です
red green plus white
赤緑プラス白
Basically red, yellow green, blue electronic paper
基本的に赤、黄緑、青の電子ペーパー
all added up
すべて合計した
it's sunlight
それは太陽光です
So in fact sunlight is also an additive color display
つまり、実際には太陽光も加法混色ディスプレイなのです
So what we just said so far
これまでに述べたこと
They're all talking about elimination-type complementary colors
消去法補色の話ばかりだ
But we're going back now to the sun at the beginning
でも僕らは今、始まりの太陽に戻るんだ
Sunlight is an additive color
太陽光は加法混色です
Because the application of matter that we are going to talk about next
なぜなら、次に話す物質の応用だからです。
Especially the optoelectronic technology industry uses additive colors
特にオプトエレクトロニクス技術業界では加法混色が使用されています。
using a luminous substance
発光物質を使って
Luminous matter is like the sun
発光物質は太陽のようなもの
the sun is something that shines
太陽は輝くものです
Luminous substances are all additive colors
発光物質はすべて加法混色です
for example like this
たとえばこのように
In the laboratory, some so-called nanoparticles will be made
実験室では、いわゆるナノ粒子がいくつか作成されます
This is a nanoparticle made of inorganic material
無機材料でできたナノ粒子です
Then we talked about it at the beginning
それから、最初にそれについて話しました
Color rendering of inorganic materials
無機材料の演色性
and the size of its constituent elements
とその構成要素のサイズ
The size of the radius is related to
半径の大きさは次のように関係します。
So look at the various colors it presents here
ここで紹介されているさまざまな色を見てください
It is caused by the size of the nanoparticle
ナノ粒子の大きさが原因
The bigger the color, the more reddish it will be
色が大きくなるほど赤みが強くなります
the smaller you make
小さくするほど
This is towards the blue direction
こちらは青の方向です
but this is
しかし、これは
What you see is an additive color
あなたが見ているものは加法的な色です
it's something that emits light
それは光を発するものです
This material called silver light or aura
銀の光とかオーラとか呼ばれるこの物質
This is the presentation of additive color
加法混色のご紹介です
Substances that include these long-lasting auras
これらの長期持続するオーラを含む物質
It's pretty standard like this
これはかなり標準的です
Silver light, for example, we painted on that clock
たとえばあの時計に描いた銀色の光
That or the emergency exit thing that lights up
それか非常口が光るやつ
They are all luminous substances composed of these inorganic elements.
これらはすべてこれらの無機元素から構成される発光物質です。
and inside these plastic panels
そしてこのプラスチックパネルの中には
something that looks a lot like the light colors of a neon sign
ネオンサインの明るい色によく似ているもの
It's all made of silvery material
全て銀色の素材でできています
It also includes going to a concert like this or that
あんなコンサートやあんなコンサートに行くことも含まれます
Don't you take two bright sticks?
光る棒を2本持っていませんか？
It's all made of these organic substances that have undergone chemical reactions.
これらはすべて化学反応を起こした有機物質でできています。
the light emitted
発せられた光
seen by our eyes
私たちの目で見られる
What we're talking about here are all so-called additive colors.
ここで話しているのはすべて、いわゆる加法混色です。
Most of the additive colors are composed of silver or aura substances
加法混色のほとんどは銀またはオーラ物質で構成されています
There is also a silver light silver light
シルバーライトシルバーライトもあります
Where the application of silver light or aura is used
銀の光やオーラの適用が使用される場合
make your white look whiter
あなたの白をより白く見せる
This is used because we people like pure white color very much
私たち人間は真っ白な色をとても好むのでこれが使われます
including my sports socks
スポーツソックスも含めて
be very white
とても白くなってください
whiter whiter
より白く、より白く
The better it is, the more beautiful it is
良ければ良いほど美しい
There are also these clothes, you can see that there are these additives in this washing powder
こんな洋服もあります、この洗剤にはこんな添加物が入っているのがわかりますね
Under ultraviolet light it will appear blue light
紫外線を当てると青く光ります
The paper towels used in our toilets are also screw-shaped
トイレで使用しているペーパータオルもネジ型です
I won't add this thing to hand paper, because it doesn't need to be very white
あまり白い必要はないので、これを紙には追加しません
Because the paper towels are usually yellowish
ペーパータオルは黄色っぽいものが多いので
But our print is like this paper
でも私たちのプリントはこの紙のようなものです
The paper used for printing should be laid out better
印刷に使用する用紙をより適切にレイアウトする必要があります
This fluorescent substance must be added inside
この蛍光物質は内部に添加する必要があります
as seen in this picture
この写真に見られるように
On the right is the hand paper, this is A4 printing paper
右側は手提げ紙、これはA4の印刷用紙です
A4 printing paper will emit blue light when viewed under ultraviolet light
A4の印画紙を紫外線で見るとブルーライトを発します
this one doesn't
これはそうではありません
So in the case of blue light emitted
つまり、ブルーライトが発せられる場合には、
This white will look whiter
この白はもっと白く見えます
This is called a fluorescent additive, or a fluorescent whitening agent
これを蛍光添加剤、あるいは蛍光増白剤といいます。
This thing will be used in many places
これは色々なところで使われますね
Including the paper we just talked about
今話した論文も含めて
Including that cloth like that white one
あの白い布みたいなのも含めて
to look white
白く見えるように
So it must add this thing
したがって、これを追加する必要があります
will look whiter
より白く見えます
There are also many electrical supplies like that
そういう電気用品もたくさんあります
It's inside the white shell
白い殻の中です
Added all of these
これらすべてを追加しました
The so-called fluorescent whitening agent
いわゆる蛍光増白剤です。
This has an effect of making the white whiter whiter
白をより白くする効果があります
Including the white sneakers too
白いスニーカーも合わせて
This fluorescent whitening agent is added to everything.
この蛍光増白剤はあらゆるものに添加されています。
The last display
最後のディスプレイ
I will quickly talk about this ten-year relationship
この10年間の関係について簡単に話します
This has been eliminated
これは解消されました
The display method of impression tube
印象管の表示方法
It actually uses a lot of this
実際にはこれをたくさん使います
fluorescent powder in this
この中に蛍光粉が入っています
This is also a display of color called additive
これも加法と呼ばれる色の表示です
The same is true for TVs including this plasma
このプラズマを含むテレビも同様です
All rely on the glow of its fluorescent powder
すべては蛍光パウダーの輝きに依存しています
to present this picture
この写真を提示するために
This is plasma or impression tube
これは血漿または印象管です
In fact, they have all been eliminated
実際、それらはすべて排除されています。
there is another
もう一つの...がある
What this light-emitting display will use is
この発光ディスプレイが使用するものは、
We see this LED light bulb everywhere now
今ではどこでもこのLED電球を目にします
This is also a light-emitting photoelectric product
こちらも発光する光電製品です
Some semiconductor materials are used in it.
一部の半導体材料が使用されています。
substances composed of these elements
これらの元素から構成される物質
These substances after passing the current
通電後のこれらの物質
it sparks light out
それは光を発する
This phenomenon is called electroluminescence
この現象はエレクトロルミネッセンスと呼ばれます
Because the substances used here are all inorganic compounds
ここで使用される物質はすべて無機化合物であるため、
You can see that there is no carbon, hydrogen, oxygen and nitrogen in this
この中に炭素、水素、酸素、窒素が存在しないことがわかります。
elements in organic matter
有機物中の元素
So these substances are inorganic materials
したがって、これらの物質は無機物質です
It can be used as a light-emitting material for LED bulbs
LED電球の発光材料として利用可能
This LED light bulb can also be used as a screen
スクリーンとしても使えるLED電球です
This screen is super large and placed on that TV
このスクリーンは超大型で、そのテレビの上に置かれています
It's for the big screen on the wall
壁の大画面用です
This is like this popular place in Taipei City
ここは台北市の人気スポットのようです
And this is the NASDAQ CPPCC exchange
そして、これはナスダックCPPCC取引所です
150% of this big Taipei City
この大きな台北市の 150%
They're a video wall six stories high
あれは6階建てのビデオウォールだ
are lined up with LED bulbs
LED電球が並んでいます
We just looked at a few very common
ごく一般的なものをいくつか見ていきました
flat panel display
フラットパネルディスプレイ
Includes traditional acoustic tubes
従来の音響管を搭載
including deprecated
非推奨のものを含む
plasma display
プラズマディスプレイ
What still exists is this LCD
今も残っているのはこの液晶です
LCD is not an additive color display
LCDは加法混色ディスプレイではありません
It is a complementary color display
補色表示です
Because it's light passing through this colored green light sheet
この緑色のライトシートを通過する光だから
and filter out the colors we want to see
見たい色をフィルターで除外します
This is a complementary color display
補色表示です
The last thing I want to talk about is a flat panel monitor
最後に話したいのはフラットパネルモニターについてです
It is the so-called LED made of organic materials.
いわゆる有機材料で作られたLEDです。
Just now we saw that this LED is made of inorganic materials
今、この LED が無機材料でできていることがわかりました。
It is because it is composed of these inorganic elements
これらの無機元素で構成されているからです
In recent years, it has begun to appear
近年、現れ始めているのが、
It is an electric exposure display made of organic materials
有機材料を使用した電界露出型ディスプレイです
Where is this display used for?
このディスプレイはどこに使用されますか?
Both of these were also eliminated.
こちらも両方とも撤去されました。
Now
現在
Only these two things are still available in the market
まだ市場で入手できるのはこの2つだけです
Should have killed it didn't kill it
殺すべきだった、殺さなかった
see next
次を見る
This was the front page headline in that newspaper a few years ago
これは数年前のその新聞の一面の見出しでした
this samsung it spends a lot of money on a full page front page
このサムスンは全ページのトップページに多額の費用を費やしています
when that ad
その広告のとき
because they made this
彼らがこれを作ったから
This Galaxy Note
このギャラクシーノート
With this Galaxy S smartphone
このGalaxy Sスマートフォンでは
What is used here is called organic light-emitting secondary
ここで使われているのは有機発光二次電池と呼ばれるものです。
Referred to as OLED
OLEDと呼ばれる
Now this OLED can be made into a 77-inch large electronic machine
このOLEDは77インチの大型電子機器にできる
This one was recently in Las Vegas, USA
これは最近アメリカのラスベガスで行われたものです
Displayed in the Electronic Communications Exhibition
電子通信展に出展
LG shows in this
LGはこれで示します
Just like an LCD, it can be made into such a large electronic machine
液晶ディスプレイと同じで、こんなに大きな電子機械になるんですね
And it's still made into a curved surface
そしてまだ曲面になっている
very attractive
とても魅力的な
Compared with OLD, this LCD has some advantages.
OLD と比較して、この LCD にはいくつかの利点があります。
I won't talk about the time relationship
時間の関係については話さない
Its picture is clearer
その画像はより鮮明です
It has a wider viewing angle
視野角が広いです
That camera is still relatively power efficient.
そのカメラはまだ比較的電力効率が良いです。
It also has a relatively large Indian number
インド人の数も比較的多い
These organic LEs can also be used as white light
これらの有機LEは白色光としても使用できます
White light means that you add red, blue, and green together
白い光は、赤、青、緑を加えることを意味します
it will turn white and you can use it for lighting
白くなって照明として使用できます
Just like the energy-saving light bulbs in our house, we can use this instead
我が家の省エネ電球と同じように、これでも代用できます。
This glowing substance, these are all organic substances
この光る物質、すべて有機物です
It must be synthesized in the laboratory
実験室で合成する必要がある
Just like Wayne Perkins synthesized in the laboratory
ウェイン・パーキンスが実験室で合成したときのように
He wants to synthesize the medicine of kulin
彼はクリンという薬を合成したいと考えています
At that time, because he couldn't figure it out, he didn't understand the chemistry
当時は理解できなかったので化学が理解できなかった
Now we know very well
今では私たちはよく知っています
It must be designed according to his chemical structure
彼の化学構造に従って設計されなければなりません
Because different chemical structures will show different colors
化学構造が異なれば色も異なるため、
Like the one on the right hand side is red and orange
右側は赤とオレンジのようです
Yellow and green in the middle and blue on the left
真ん中が黄色と緑、左が青
Different chemical structures will produce different light colors
異なる化学構造は異なる光の色を生成します
Organic light-emitting diodes require a variety of different
有機発光ダイオードにはさまざまな要件が必要です
Luminous substances to match to make the whole screen
画面全体を構成する発光物質
This is the end
これで終わりだ
The second chapter talks a lot because I'm a chemist
私は化学者なので、第 2 章では多くのことを話します
I went to take a few photos in our laboratory
研究室に写真を撮りに行ってきました
Photos of chemical synthesis for everyone to see
誰でも見られる化学合成の写真
Start with the simplest glass bottle
最もシンプルなガラス瓶から始めましょう
What we ended up with is this material that glows red
出来上がったのがこの赤く光る素材です
But this red fluorescent material was originally something like this
でもこの赤い蛍光体は元々はこんな感じだったんです
Reflected to a stage like here
こんなステージに映る
a can of stuff that becomes usima black
ウシマブラックになるものの缶詰
What you want is from inside a can of this usima black
欲しいのはこのウシマブラックの缶の中から
separate it
分けて
You see this red substance over here
ここにこの赤い物質が見えます
There will be yellow and green fluorescent substances in the same can
同じ缶の中に黄色と緑色の蛍光体が入っています
You use this separation technique
この分離テクニックを使用します
after separating it
それを分けた後
Collect this jar separately
この瓶を別に集めてください
After removing the solvent
溶剤を除去した後
solid will produce
固体が生成します
We collect it in this glass bottle
このガラス瓶に集めます
This is a typical chemistry lab
ここは典型的な化学実験室です
A practice of synthetic materials
合成素材の実践
This is what we use modern chemical technology
これが現代の化学技術を利用したものです
Prepare this colored substance by yourself
この色のついたものは自分で用意します
It's just that this is an invention
ただ、これは発明です
Its light-type material is the same as that of Perkin William 150 years ago
ライトタイプの素材は150年前のパーキン・ウィリアムのものと同じ
Of course it can't be the same
もちろん同じにはなれないけど
they don't have that modern equipment
彼らはそんな近代的な設備を持っていない
There is no chemical laboratory like it is available now
現在利用できるような化学実験室はありません
This is an example of our own actual
これは私たち自身の実際の例です
We designed and synthesized a chemical substance like this
私たちはこのような化学物質を設計・合成しました
it is fluorescent red
蛍光レッドです
It can be made inside this element of the red OLED
赤色OLEDのこの要素内で作ることができます
Is it a pixel like this?
こんな感じのピクセルでしょうか？
It is used in Samsung smartphones
サムスンのスマートフォンに採用されている
It's just that there are about 600 such things on the panel of the mobile phone
携帯電話のパネルにはそのようなものが約600個あるだけです
stuffed in here
ここに詰め込まれている
Each one is made very small
一つ一つがとても小さく作られています
So the resolution of this picture can be increased to a very high
したがって、この画像の解像度は非常に高くすることができます
We are not a panel
私たちはパネルではありません
We're just demonstrating in the lab that
私たちは研究室でそれを実証しているだけです
we can do it too
私たちにもできます
We just made a big one, which is easier to make.
作りやすい大きめのものを作りました。
A real panel phone needs millions of pieces to squeeze it inside
実際のパネル電話を内部に押し込むには何百万もの部品が必要です
So each one is made very, very small
そのため、それぞれが非常に小さく作られています
This can be regarded as the summary of the last report of today’s knowledge miss
これは、今日のナレッジミスの最後のレポートの要約と見なすことができます
I'm talking about dyes from that
そこから染料について話しているのです
From the traditional dyeing and finishing process
伝統的な染色と仕上げのプロセスから
The inventor is this William Bergin
発明者はこのウィリアム・バーギンです
We now call him the father of chemical engineering
私たちは現在彼を化学工学の父と呼んでいます
The production of the original dyes was based on the application of its disappearing color presentation
消えていく色の表現を応用したオリジナル染料の制作
Speaking of the application of optoelectronics in the future?
将来のオプトエレクトロニクスの応用について言えば?
Everything becomes the presentation of additive colors
すべては加法混色の表現となる
Either subtractive or additive
減算または加算のいずれか
These colored substances are used
このような着色物質が使用されています
One is the color of bone protection
1つは骨の保護の色です
One is the color of the light it emits
一つは発する光の色です
I will talk about the application of this fashionable technology later.
このファッショナブルなテクノロジーの応用については後ほど説明します。
Includes various panels
各種パネルも付属
The panel of the mobile phone or the screen of the laptop
携帯電話のパネルまたはラップトップの画面
Or now we see that they have done the electronic machine 77 inches
あるいは、今では彼らが 77 インチの電子機器を開発したことがわかります。
Such a large electronic screen can be used with these luminous substances
このような大きな電子スクリーンは、これらの発光体で使用できます。
In addition, it is still in the development stage
また、まだ開発段階ですので、
Solar cells are also the last manifestation of the application of these dyes
太陽電池は、これらの色素の応用の最後の現れでもあります。
This era has progressed from about 150 years ago.
約150年前からこの時代が進んできました。
William Perkins to the present technology transition
ウィリアム・パーキンスによる現在のテクノロジーの変遷
It's actually I think it's unbelievably hot
実際、信じられないほど暑いと思います
You would never have thought to say
あなたは決してこう言うとは思わなかっただろう
These dyes can be applied to current technologies like these
これらの染料は、次のような現在の技術に応用できます。
Well, it's almost time now
さて、そろそろ時間です
Ok, thank you Dr. Chen for the wonderful colorful world
OK、チェン博士、素晴らしいカラフルな世界をありがとう
Now you are welcome to ask questions
ご質問も大歓迎です
please
お願いします
Thank you teacher Caiying for teaching me twice that one should be two lottery draws
Caiying 先生、宝くじは 2 回引くべきだと 2 回教えてくれてありがとう
There should be a problem with improving the color
色の改善に問題があるはずです
You should also remember if you reversed the color or said that you were bathed
色が反転しているのか、それとも浴びていると言われているのかも覚えておく必要があります。
I see I see so it's too hot girl
なるほどなるほど、暑すぎるガール
Everything is reflected, what I see is white
全てが反射して 見えるものは白い
but sometimes i see
でも時々見るよ
I'll try it if it's a color bomb black
カラーボムブラックなら試してみます
But obviously there is too much fire shining on it
しかし明らかに火が照りすぎている
I still think it is
今でもそうだと思う
but say so
でもそう言ってください
It's supposed to be black and suck all the light out
黒くて光をすべて吸い取ってしまうはずだ
is it?
それは...ですか？
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
why say still
なぜまだ言うのか
You said this situation is actually
この状況が実際にあるとあなたは言いました
It is absorbing and reflecting at the same time
吸収と反射を同時に行っている
coexist at the same time
同時に共存する
The example I just gave is very
先ほど挙げた例は非常に
The dichotomy is that there is reflection and there is no absorption
二項対立とは、反射があり、吸収が存在しないことを意味します
Or if there is absorption there is no reflection
または、吸収がある場合は反射はありません
In fact most things are both
実際、ほとんどのことは両方です
So you're clearly a black thing
つまり、あなたは明らかに黒人です
You can still see its light reflected
その光が反射しているのがまだ見えます
and its reflection
そしてその反映
Because its surface is very flat
表面がとても平らなので、
Very flat surfaces reflect light easily
非常に平らな表面は光を反射しやすい
But it's transparent again
でもまた透明になった
so it has part of the light
だからそれは光の一部を持っています
actually penetrates through
実際に貫通する
absorbed by its dye
その色素に吸収される
appear black
黒く見える
But there is some light
でも少し光もある
it doesn't pass through
それは通過しません
it is the surface
それは表面です
smooth things are reflected
滑らかなものが反映されます
So you'll see this sickness
それでこの病気がわかるでしょう
obviously black
明らかに黒い
Why can I still see the light reflected?
反射した光がまだ見えるのはなぜですか?
Then you can send more
その後、さらに送信できます
Because like us a kettle keeps filling
なぜなら私たちと同じようにやかんは常に満たされ続けるからです
then it will break
それなら壊れるだろう
The balloon keeps inflating
風船は膨らみ続けます
will break
壊れるだろう
that light is energy
その光はエネルギーです
That one assumes the black car is over there
あれは黒い車があそこにあると仮定している
it's shiny
輝いています
Always absorbing, always absorbing, always absorbing
常に吸収、常に吸収、常に吸収
Why doesn't it seem broken or broken
壊れても壊れても見えないのはなぜですか
Because that energy is not yet big enough
そのエネルギーはまだ十分大きくないから
like that
そのように
But it keeps absorbing light and always absorbing light
でもそれは光を吸収し続ける、そして常に光を吸収する
An accompanying series is
付属シリーズは、
it's getting hotter and hotter
ますます暑くなってきました
But it's so hot that it doesn't mean that the temperature keeps going up.
でも、暑いからといって気温が上がり続けるわけではありません。
it goes to a point
それはある地点まで行く
Because the object itself is exposed to sunlight
物体自体が太陽光にさらされているため
exposure to light
光への曝露
it emits heat
熱を発します
it will reach a balance
それはバランスに達するでしょう
It is also dissipating heat
熱も逃がします
light keeps shining
光は輝き続ける
It also keeps cooling
また、冷え続けます
watch this at last
最後にこれを見てください
The total energy and its released energy will finally reach a balance
総エネルギーとその放出エネルギーは最終的に均衡に達する
For example, most of our experience is
たとえば、私たちの経験のほとんどは、
under the sun
太陽の下で
The body of the car will be sunburned, right?
車のボディは日焼けしますよね？
That temperature is about 50 degrees C
その温度は約50℃です
The degree of heat dissipation has something to do with your material.
熱放散の程度は素材と関係があります
Most of them will reach a stage of equilibrium
それらのほとんどは平衡段階に達するでしょう
If you really use very strong light to illuminate, for example, laser light
実際にレーザー光などの非常に強い光を使用する場合
That heat is far greater than its ability to relax
熱はリラックスする能力をはるかに超えています
Your metal will be melted away, right?
金属が溶けてしまいますよね？
This depends entirely on whether your input and output have reached a balance
これはインプットとアウトプットのバランスが取れているかどうかに完全に依存します
ask holy teacher
聖なる先生に尋ねてください
The dyes that everyone sells are for visible light absorption and reflection
みんなが売っている染料は可視光線の吸収と反射用です
developed
発展した
Are there any dyes for invisible light
不可視光線に対応する染料はありますか
have
もつ
I just don't remember saying
ただ言ったことは覚えていない
because
なぜなら
We can't see without light
私たちは光がなければ見ることができません
Today I mainly focus on what we can see with our eyes
今日は主に目に見えるものに焦点を当てます
usually visible light
通常目に見える光
Then what you're talking about is, for example, the light outside the arc of a mirror.
では、あなたが話しているのは、たとえば、鏡の円弧の外側にある光のことです。
Or infrared light and ultraviolet light
あるいは赤外線や紫外線
it is also part of the light
それも光の一部です
but our eyes can't see
でも私たちの目は見えません
But this one has a dye like this
でもこれはこんな感じの染料があるんです
If it is a luminous dye
光る染料なら
That is, the wavelength of your light should exceed about 700 nanometers
つまり、光の波長は約 700 ナノメートルを超える必要があります。
That is the infrared light, the mirror arc or the outer light of the mirror arc.
それは、赤外光、ミラーアーク、またはミラーアークの外側の光である。
If its wavelength is shorter than about 450
波長が約450より短い場合
that becomes ultraviolet light
それが紫外線になる
Then it's about solar cells
続いて太陽電池の話です
Because visible light makes up only a small fraction of the
可視光線はほんの一部しか占めていないため、
yes
はい
So if it's the dye
それで、それが染料なら
Is it possible to apply in
での申請は可能ですか？
Can make full use of solar energy
太陽エネルギーを最大限に活用できる
A visible dye has a wavelength of
目に見える染料の波長は
in the range of visible light
可視光の範囲で
But the sun is actually very wide
しかし、太陽は実際には非常に広いです
Depends on whether your material is made of organic materials or inorganic materials
材料が有機材料でできているか、無機材料でできているかによって異なります
Inorganic materials are the solar panels we see on the market now
無機材料は現在市場で見られるソーラーパネルです
Those are all composed of thin or inorganic elements
それらはすべて薄い要素または無機要素で構成されています
The range of light absorption is very long
光の吸収範囲が非常に長い
absorbs in the infrared range
赤外線範囲で吸収します
so yes indeed
はい、確かに
We do research in the hope that
私たちはそう願って研究を行っています
Are we using organic materials?
有機材料を使用していますか?
We just want to say that the range of organic materials that can absorb light
私たちが言いたいのは、光を吸収できる有機材料の範囲は次のとおりです。
stretch him out into the range of infrared light
彼を赤外線の範囲内に伸ばします
But it's not easy to do it with organic materials
しかし、有機材料でそれを行うのは簡単ではありません
Not as easy to make as inorganic materials
無機材料ほど製造が容易ではない
Ok please finally because
わかりました、ようやくできるようになりますので
The four questions
4つの質問
That is to say, the sun is yellowish in the morning
つまり、朝の太陽は黄色がかっています
What was his eye shadow that was reddish that night
あの夜赤く染まった彼のアイシャドウは何だったのか
The second one is the spectrum of sunlight and fluorescent lamps
2つ目は太陽光と蛍光灯のスペクトルです。
is it the same
それは同じですか
Isn't there a glass that allows the sunlight to pass through
太陽光を通すガラスはないのでしょうか？
But fluorescent lamps can't see through
でも蛍光灯は透けない
Is there a way through this
これを突破する方法はありますか
Then the Egyptian you just mentioned is
それでは、あなたが今言ったエジプト人は
The latest synthetic
最新の合成
you want to hear that topic in england
イギリスでその話題を聞きたいですか
again the first human
再び最初の人間
Synthetic pigments, these two
合成顔料、この２つ
where is the difference
違いはどこにありますか
good
良い
The last one is to say
最後に言うのは、
black should be
黒であるべきです
Easiest to absorb light
光を吸収しやすい
But in nature why
しかし自然界ではなぜ
Why is it developed that the nocturnal element is earth-colored to absorb light
なぜ夜行性の要素が光を吸収するために土色になったのか
No development is black to absorb light
光を吸収して黒色になる現像はありません
It's fun for me to answer your questions one by one
質問に一つ一つ答えていくのが楽しいです
the first you say that
あなたが最初にそれを言うのは
morning dusk
朝夕暮れ
Why is the color of the sun's light different from the color of the light in the middle of the day?
太陽の光の色はなぜ昼間の光の色と違うのでしょうか?
this fact
この事実
It has nothing to do with the material, it's all because
それは素材とは何の関係もありません、それはすべての理由です
So the light, the morning light or the yellow light
だから光、朝の光、あるいは黄色い光
it shines on the surface of the earth
それは地球の表面で輝いています
It has to penetrate the thicker atmosphere
厚い大気を貫通しなければならない
The sun is directly above in the schedule
スケジュールでは太陽が真上にあります
the depth of the atmosphere through which the earth passes
地球が通過する大気の深さ
day and dusk, morning and dusk
昼と夕暮れ、朝と夕暮れ
The thickness of the atmosphere it penetrates is different
貫く大気の厚さが違う
Are there many in the atmosphere?
大気中にはたくさんいるでしょうか？
presence of floating particles
浮遊粒子の存在
These floating particles and your light, light
浮遊する粒子とあなたの光、光
The incoming light, the sun's rays will make some
入ってくる光、太陽光線が何らかの影響を与えるでしょう
phenomenon of diffraction or refraction
回折または屈折の現象
This will make your light the sun's rays
そうすればあなたの光は太陽光線になります
Certain wavelengths of light are particularly intensified
光の特定の波長が特に強化されます
Some wavelengths of light are particularly weak
光の一部の波長は特に弱い
so you would render
だからあなたはレンダリングするでしょう
Morning and evening light are different
朝と夜の光は違う
this is
これは
This is actually a physical optics reason
これは実際には物理的な光学的な理由です
I'm a chemistry student, in fact I'm not very
私は化学の学生ですが、実はあまり得意ではありません
But the first reason you just asked
しかし、あなたが今尋ねた最初の理由は
Basically we interpret it this way
基本的にはこのように解釈します
because it passes through the atmosphere at different thicknesses
異なる厚さで大気中を通過するため
There are many floating particles in the atmosphere
大気中には浮遊粒子がたくさんあります
this will diffract
これは回折します
This existence is an optical phenomenon
この存在は光学現象です
will change the wavelength of some part of that sunlight
その太陽光の一部の波長が変化します
Then the second question you asked is
次に、あなたが尋ねた2番目の質問は、
Black
黒
no you asked
いいえ、あなたが尋ねました
that glass is
そのガラスは
Glass sun rays can pass through
ガラスの太陽光線は通過します
Can the fluorescent lamp work?
蛍光灯は使えるのでしょうか？
No
いいえ
you ask a question
あなたは質問します
Is the light from a fluorescent tube the same as the sun's light?
蛍光管の光は太陽の光と同じですか？
Is the spectrum
スペクトルですか
is the same spectrum
同じスペクトルです
I say different
私は違うと言います
is there a way to make a glass
ガラスを作る方法はありますか
That is to say, the outside cannot see the inside
つまり外からは中が見えない
But you can see it from the outside
でも外から見てもわかるよ
just according to it
ちょうどそれに応じて
pure glass no way
純粋なガラスは無理
but you can on the surface of the glass
でもガラスの表面ならできるよ
Apply some material to achieve
達成するためにいくつかのマテリアルを適用します
the purpose of this
この目的
For example, the most traditional way is to
たとえば、最も伝統的な方法は次のとおりです。
you are like a mirror
あなたは鏡のようです
You can add a reflective one inside
内側に反射材を追加できます
translucent reflector
半透明の反射板
You can't see the inside from the outside
外からは中が見えない
But you can still see the outside
でも外はまだ見えます
But when the website
しかし、ウェブサイトが
outside or see inside
外を見るか中を見るか
I mean use them sunlight and daylight
つまり、太陽光と日光を使用するということです
The difference with the spectrum
スペクトルとの違い
That is to say, let the sunlight pass through
つまり、太陽光を通すということです。
Let the sunlight not see through
太陽光が透けないようにしてください
As far as the website is concerned, sunlight cannot penetrate through it.
ウェブサイトに関する限り、太陽光は透過しません。
Even if you throw it outside at night, you can't see inside.
夜外に放り出しても中は見えません。
this is a bit difficult
これは少し難しいです
because the solar spectrum
なぜなら太陽のスペクトルは
basically covers all the rays
基本的にすべての光線をカバーします
If you want to let the sun's rays
太陽の光を浴びたいなら
If everything penetrates the past
すべてが過去を貫くなら
should say so
そう言うべきだ
Fluorescent Tubes It Doesn't Cover All
蛍光管 すべてを網羅しているわけではありません
All bands of sunlight
太陽光のすべての帯域
So you can do a thing
それであなたは何かをすることができます
Limit light from fluorescent tubes
蛍光管の光を制限する
Penetration does not penetrate
浸透が浸透しない
but you are hard
でもあなたは難しいです
make a sun ray
太陽光線を作る
make a glass plate
ガラス板を作る
Selectively let the sun's rays penetrate
太陽光線を選択的に透過させます
impenetrable
侵入できない
Because the solar spectrum is a relatively complete band
太陽のスペクトルは比較的完全なバンドであるため、
On the contrary, it is easier to limit the light of fluorescent tubes
逆に蛍光管の光を制限しやすい
because it's not all
それがすべてではないから
So you just put some fluorescent tubes
それで、蛍光管をいくつか置くだけです
The material that absorbs fluorescent tubes
蛍光管を吸収する素材
sit in the glass
ガラスの中に座る
In this way, the light of the fluorescent tube cannot penetrate
これにより、蛍光管の光は透過できなくなります。
But the sun is still
でも太陽はまだある
Because the sun's rays have a wider range of rays in its spectrum
太陽光線はスペクトル内でより広い光のスペクトルを持っているため、
But it's not hard to do it the other way around
でも逆にやれば難しくないよ
I just wish the sun could come in
太陽が入ってくればいいのに
it was the time of fluorescent tubes
蛍光管の時代だった
It is so that at night, the outside cannot see the inside
夜になると外から中が見えないようになっています
Then why didn't this thing come out?
では、なぜこれが出てこなかったのでしょうか？
Because the spectrum of fluorescent tubes is relatively narrow
蛍光管のスペクトルは比較的狭いため、
we are easier
私たちはもっと簡単です
The narrow spectrum makes it impossible to get in and out
スペクトルが狭いため出入りが不可能
But if it is wide, we must make it all to absorb the sun's rays
でも広いなら、太陽光線を吸収するために全力を尽くしなければなりません
Then, of course, sunlight will be absorbed.
そうすると当然太陽光も吸収されてしまいます。
but you can make a tube that absorbs fluorescent light
しかし、蛍光を吸収する管を作ることはできます。
but some sun rays remain
しかし、太陽の光は少し残っています
not absorbed by it
それに吸収されない
do it the other way around
逆にやってみろよ
But it's not easy to do it the other way around
しかし、その逆を行うのは簡単ではありません
It is easier for us to limit things with a narrower spectrum
より狭いスペクトルで物事を制限する方が簡単です
But there is no way to limit the full spectrum of things
しかし、物事の全範囲を制限する方法はありません
like this
このような
Ig2 and that
Ig2とそれ
Both are actually the first inventions
実はどちらも最初の発明です
But Ig's invention color uses different materials
ただし、イグの発明色は別の素材を使用しています
Ig2 uses inorganic materials
Ig2は無機材料を使用します
Purkin I also use organic materials
プルキンもオーガニック素材を使用しています
Inorganic materials are virtually unchanged in their composition
無機材料はその組成がほとんど変化しません
It is derived from these fine acids, fine acid stones, malachite
これらの微細な酸、微細な酸性石、マラカイトに由来します。
It is made up of atoms or ions of metals
金属の原子またはイオンで構成されています
it's just throwing it together and re-creating it
それは単にそれを組み合わせて再作成するだけです
Its composition has not been altered at all
その組成はまったく変わっていません
it just reformulates it
それを再定式化するだけです
Purkin-Wheel, different
プルキンホイール、違う
It is dismantling the original molecule
元の分子を解体している
put it back together again
もう一度元に戻します
That's a chemical reaction
それは化学反応です
Although the Egyptians are also doing chemical reactions
エジプト人も化学反応を起こしているが
The chemical reaction between the two is not the same
両者の化学反応は同じではありません
One is organic synthesis and the other is inorganic synthesis
1つは有機合成、もう1つは無機合成です。
So if you speak in a broad sense, there is nothing wrong
広い意味で言えば何も問題ない
Egypt can also be said to be the first color to be artificially formulated.
エジプトは、初めて人工的に調合された色とも言えます。
Purkin-Wheel is equal to creating something from scratch
Purkin-Wheel は、ゼロから何かを作成することに等しい
Invent a new substance
新しい物質を発明する
This is a place where the two are not the same
ここは二つが同じではない場所です
We also only call Pokéware the father of chemical engineering
また、ポケウェアを化学工学の父と呼ぶだけです。
because it lived in modern times
それは現代に生きているからです
The Egyptians made that color at that time
当時エジプト人がその色を作った
But because it was too early
でも、早すぎたので
There is no way to say that an industry will be produced.
産業が生まれるとは言い切れない。
That era was a bit different
あの時代はちょっと違った
if the egyptian is later
エジプト人が後だったら
Maybe at that time they will also send
もしかしたらその時に彼らも送ってくれるかもしれない
At that time, an industrial-scale production of this scale will be developed.
その時には、この規模の工業規模の生産が開発されるでしょう。
professor
教授
that is that black
それはあの黒です
Black should be the most absorbing color
黒は最も吸収性の高い色であるはずです
Why Nature Is Green To Absorb That
なぜ自然はそれを吸収するために緑色なのか
Leaf green tree
葉緑の木
no
いいえ
Black means that several places have been absorbed
黒はいくつかの場所が吸収されていることを意味します
absorbed it, right?
それを吸収しましたね？
that's right
それは正しい
If all the sun's rays are absorbed
太陽光線がすべて吸収されたら
just want it
ただ欲しいだけ
All are absorbed everywhere
すべてはどこにでも吸収されます
just rely on
ただ頼ってください
by that black substance
その黒い物質によって
but you can see this nature
でもこの性質を見ることができます
except something is black
何かが黒いことを除いて
charcoal is black
炭は黒いです
Nothing seems black
何も黒く見えない
The charcoal is not actually
木炭は実際にはそうではありません
United speaking is not an organic substance
ユナイテッドスピーキングは有機物質ではありません
As far as we are concerned, there is life and there is no life
私たちに関する限り、生命は存在しますが、生命は存在しません
words to distinguish in the future
将来区別するための言葉
so living things
だから生き物
You'd be hard-pressed to find something all black one at a time
真っ黒なものを一度に見つけるのは難しいでしょう
This if you really want to get to the bottom of it
本当に本質を知りたいならこれ
You may want to ask God about this
これについては神様に聞いてみるといいかもしれません
I do not want
欲しくない
it the birth of this life of life
それはこの生命の誕生です
made of organic matter
有機物でできている
But organic matter is rarely seen and said to be completely black
しかし有機物はほとんど見られず真っ黒と言われています
So I am more like this. Did you answer your question?
質問には答えられましたか?
That laver is purple
その海苔は紫色です
The pigment absorption of that seaweed
その海藻の色素吸収
Can wide and other abilities be entered into the wall at night?
夜にワイドなどの能力を壁に入れることはできますか？
you asked very well
あなたはよく尋ねました
That seaweed
あの海苔
In fact it is because the color is very dark
実際は色が濃いので
after you dilute the color
色を薄めた後
it's not actually black
実際には黒ではありません
it's actually purple
実際は紫です
Otherwise, it wouldn't be called laver.
そうでなければ海苔とは言えないでしょう。
It's just because the color is very dark
ただ色が濃いので
But you go to analyze its color in fact
でも実際にその色を分析してみると
it's not actually black
実際には黒ではありません
it's actually purple
実際は紫です
of a certain color
特定の色の
OK, ask the professor
OK、教授に聞いてください
Just now we talked about asking the professor
先ほど教授に聞いてみようと話しました。
Use of Exciting Phosphors and Non-Exciting Phosphors
励起蛍光体と非励起蛍光体の使用
where is the biggest difference
最大の違いはどこですか
There are also pros and cons of both
また、どちらにもメリットとデメリットがあります
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
because of time
時間のせいで
We're going to get it down to that detail
そういった細かいところまでやっていきます
you ask me questions
あなたは私に質問します
In fact, it is my research
実はこれは私の研究です
where the expertise is doing
専門知識がどこで行われているか
Its priorities actually have their own priorities. Let me first say that what I am best at is organic light-emitting diodes.
優先順位にはそれぞれ優先順位がありますが、最初に言っておきますが、私が最も得意とするのは有機発光ダイオードです。
The two things lead to a very different manufacturing process. The manufacturing process of organic light-emitting diodes is not like that of inorganic light-emitting diodes.
有機発光ダイオードの製造プロセスは、無機発光ダイオードの製造プロセスとは異なります。
There will be no high-temperature processing stage, because the materials are different,
材料が異なるため、高温処理段階はありません。
It makes all very thin films, and the inorganic must use high heat to perform the fusion action.
非常に薄いフィルムを作成するため、無機物の融合作用を実行するには高熱を使用する必要があります。
Because the material is different, organic actually does not need high temperature, it uses a little temperature, about 100 degrees C is enough,
オーガニックは素材が違うので実際には高温は必要なく、少し温度を使いますが100℃程度で十分ですが、
In fact, inorganic materials need to use 300 or 400 degrees C to make thin films. This is because the manufacturing process is different.
実際、無機材料は製造プロセスが異なるため、薄膜を作るには300℃や400℃の温度が必要です。
The difference in the manufacturing process will lead to the difference in the equipment you use when making it.
製造工程の違いは、作る際に使用する設備の違いにつながります。
Using high heat to make films, the equipment is very expensive
フィルムの製造には高熱を使用するため、装置は非常に高価です
consumes energy
エネルギーを消費します
Organic does not require high heat
オーガニックは高熱を必要としない
So its equipment is different
装備が違うので
Again, because it is not used for high temperature and high heat
繰り返しになりますが、高温・高熱には使用しませんので
so it can sit on this soft board
このソフトボードの上に座ることができます
Because generally we talk about soft plastic sheets
一般的にプラスチックシートのような柔らかさについて話しているからです
You can bend when you sit on a soft surface
柔らかい面に座ると曲がることがあります
Bending Now Everyone's Talking
今、誰もが話題にしているベンディング
The scoopable panel is an attractive application
すくえるパネルは魅力的なアプリケーションです
Inorganic materials because of the need to use high heat
高熱を必要とするため無機材料
so it can't sit on a soft board
だからソフトボードには座れない
So what about this inorganic LED?
では、この無機LEDはどうでしょうか？
It can't be made into a curved or fishable display
湾曲したディスプレイやフィッシュ可能なディスプレイにすることはできません
no way
とんでもない
Because if you want to be fishable, you must sit on a hard board
釣りができるようになりたいなら、硬いボードに座らなければならないからです
It is due to high heat
高熱のせいです
no way to sit on the plastic sheet
ビニールシートの上には座れない
The plastic sheet just melts, so there's no way to do that.
ビニールシートが溶けてしまうだけなので仕方がありません。
Then there's both because that
それなら両方あるから
It's a lot of telecommunications
通信量が多いですね
In fact, there is something different
実は違うものがあるのです
So it actually varies in efficiency
つまり、実際には効率が異なります
And if you talk about the lighting
そして照明について言えば
There will be some difference in brightness
多少の明るさの違いはあるでしょうが
In terms of efficiency and brightness
効率と明るさの点で
Or is it actually better to be inorganic?
それとも本当は無機的なほうが良いのでしょうか？
Organic is worse
オーガニックの方がダメだよ
So each has pros and cons
したがって、それぞれに長所と短所があります
Also, organic materials are cheaper to make
また、有機材料は製造コストが安くなります
inorganic material
無機的材料
I will use some expensive and rare metals for the net
高価なレアメタルをネットに使用します
that will be more expensive
それはもっと高価になります
So in terms of cost
それでコストの面で言うと
Organic materials are so-called OLEDs
有機材料はいわゆるOLEDです
cost is cheaper
コストが安くなります
But this is entangled again
しかし、これがまた絡む
That is to say but its organic OLED
つまり有機OLEDですが
Its efficiency and brightness are relatively poor
効率と明るさが比較的悪い
So in order to make up for this efficiency and brightness
この効率と明るさを補うために
you do more
あなたはもっとやります
So it's cheap but not really cheap
つまり、安いですが、実際には安くはありません
This is where many issues are entangled together.
ここには多くの問題が複雑に絡み合っています。
But basically they have their own strengths
しかし基本的には彼らにはそれぞれの強みがある
right
右
How does this matter in simple terms
簡単に言えば、これはどのような意味を持つのでしょうか
There are many things involved
たくさんのことが関係しています
good
良い
later
後で
Professor I want to ask a simple question
先生、素朴な質問がしたいのですが
Is this kind of light-emitting secondary body harmful to health?
この種の発光二次体は健康に有害ですか?
Because I see that mobile phones are becoming more and more common now
携帯電話がますます普及しているのがわかるからです
Small-sized big-sized TVs keep getting bigger
小型テレビも大型テレビも大型化が進む
colorful
カラフル
But my thought is whether it is harmful to our health
しかし私の考えは、それが私たちの健康に害を及ぼすかどうかです
then if there is harm
それで害があるなら
how much it hurts
どれくらい痛いですか
This question has been raised by many people
この質問は多くの人から提起されました
In fact it's
実際、それは
because it
なぜならそれは
Basically the light it emits
基本的にそれが発する光
It is very similar to the traditional light
従来のライトと非常によく似ています
If you want to explore carefully, say
注意深く探索したい場合は、次のように言います。
That
それか
what kind of light
どのような光ですか
that is
あれは
it
それ
Is light harmful to the human body more or less
光は多かれ少なかれ人体に有害ですか
This is not easy to define clearly
これを明確に定義するのは簡単ではありません
Generally we talk
一般的に私たちは話します
Ultraviolet light can be harmful to our body
紫外線は私たちの体に害を及ぼす可能性があります
But the traditional glowing things
しかし伝統的にこれらの光るものは
It actually has a lot of UV light too
実は紫外線も多いんです
that for example
それは例えば
As for these relatively modern LED light bulbs
これらの比較的最近のLED電球は
or that energy saving light bulb
またはその省エネ電球
Its ultraviolet light content is also no more than
紫外線含有量も次のとおりです。
Generally, where do the light bulbs come from?
一般に、電球はどこから来ますか?
Because the light diagrams of the two are actually a bit different
両者の光の図は実際には少し異なるため
so its ultraviolet part
つまり紫外線部分
In fact, there is indeed a difference
実際には確かに違いがあります
But the difference between the two
しかし、両者の違いは、
i don't know
わからない
To what extent is it harmful to human health?
人間の健康にどの程度有害ですか?
Of course, if you look like this in any January of this year
もちろん、今年の1月にあなたがこのように見えたら
under the sun
太陽の下で
Of course that effect I will often
もちろんその効果はよくあります
will show up
現れます
On the contrary, on the contrary, what I will say later is to say
逆に、逆に、後で言うことは、
Current lighting fixtures
現在の照明器具
Much brighter than traditional lighting fixtures
従来の照明器具よりもはるかに明るい
On the contrary, the damage of this is greater than the amount of ultraviolet light.
むしろ紫外線の量よりもこちらのダメージのほうが大きいです。
Because too much light always hurts the eyes
光が多すぎると常に目を痛めるため
So now a lot of lighting is changed to LED lighting
現在、多くの照明がLED照明に変更されています
That light is very bright, isn't it?
その光はとても明るいですね。
will be bright enough to dazzle
眩しいほど明るいでしょう
traditional lamps
伝統的なランプ
because it's not that bright
そんなに明るくないから
So its damage to the eyes is actually relatively slight
したがって、目へのダメージは実際には比較的軽微です
If you look at the intensity of the light
光の強さを見てみると
there would be a worrying place like this
こんな心配なところもあるだろう
It takes a long time to be exposed like this
こうやって露出するのには時間がかかる
to show this symptom
この症状を示すために
Is it the so-called light pollution?
いわゆる光害でしょうか？
light pollution
光害
It's too bright, just don't look at it if it's too bright
明るすぎる、明るすぎる場合は見ないでください
Why is there so much light on this point
なぜこの点についてこれほど多くの光が当てられているのか
ok, is there any problem
わかりました、何か問題はありますか
OK
OK
How to solve the toxicity of dye
染料の毒性を解決する方法
dye toxicity
染料の毒性
you say this these dyes
あなたはこれを言います、これらの染料
In fact, it's more or less toxic.
実際、それは多かれ少なかれ有毒です。
How to deal with it
対処方法
Just like the general dye toxicity solution
一般的な染料毒性溶液と同様
Meltase
メルターゼ
let red settle
赤を落ち着かせる
What method do we use for general dyes
一般的な染料はどのような方法で染められるのでしょうか？
to analyze to quantify
分析する 定量化する
that is an analytical tool
それは分析ツールです
to do quantitative testing
定量的なテストを行う
For example, what happened to them a while ago?
たとえば、少し前に彼らに何が起こったのでしょうか？
Didn't the industry peer ratio have to be analyzed?
業界同業比率を分析する必要はなかったのでしょうか?
How much is there in it?
中にはいくら入っていますか？
is the same method
同じ方法です
is using the same method
同じ方法を使用しています
Food testing for those various ingredients
さまざまな食材の食品検査
Some of it is used, Zhi Puyi is doing the inspection
一部使用済み、志溥儀が検査中
Some are for actual quantitative analysis
一部は実際の定量分析用です
go to assess say
査定に行って言う
Inside content of multiple tubes
複数のチューブの内部内容
the technique is the same
テクニックは同じです
There is no need to rely on any special method
特別な方法に頼る必要はありません
good
良い
Why does some of the fuel recede and some
燃料の一部が後退し、一部が後退するのはなぜですか
oh
おお
That one is destroyed by chemicals
あれは化学薬品で破壊される
Organic matter is easily explained as
有機物を簡単に説明すると、
I also said at the beginning
冒頭でも言いましたが
The shape of that color is because of its
その色の形は、
many double bonds
二重結合がたくさんある
Carbon-carbon double bonds accumulate together
炭素-炭素二重結合が蓄積する
After the light shines for a long time
光が長く輝いた後
Or after it shines for a long time
あるいは長時間輝いた後
Some of that double bond will be destroyed
その二重結合の一部が破壊されます
After the double bond is broken
二重結合が切れた後
after its number dwindles
その数が減った後
its color will disappear completely
その色は完全に消えてしまいます
That inorganic material is another way of explaining
無機材料は別の説明方法です
is its color
その色です
is in fact related to its constituent elements
実はその構成要素に関係しているのです
Oxidation state is related
酸化状態が関係している
after a long time
長い時間が経ってから
Those oxidation states will be oxidized by air
これらの酸化状態は空気により酸化されます。
right
右
Once its oxidation state is changed
酸化状態が変化すると
Its color will also be changed
色も変わります
that often just disappears
それはしばしば消えてしまいます
This is to see whether it is human pigment dye
これは人体色素かどうかを調べるためのものです
There will be this problem of getting this fading
この色褪せの問題が発生するでしょう
It's just a matter of time
それは時間の問題です
ok one last question this way in the middle
OK、最後の質問はこの真ん中です
So, how do you tell the difference between the fluorescent light and the aura?
では、蛍光灯とオーラの違いはどうやって見分けるのでしょうか？
I could spend an hour explaining to you
あなたに説明するのに1時間かかってもいいよ
This leads to the basic phenomenon of photophysics.
これは光物理学の基本現象につながります。
yes in short
はい、要するに
The length of life of their light is not the same
ライトの寿命は同じではありません
Theoretically, they are produced from different states
理論的には、それらは異なる状態から生成されます。
So if you're going to say what can we do
それで、私たちに何ができるかというと、
eyes can't tell the difference
目では違いがわかりません
Because of the difference in the speed of his time
時間の速さが違うから
beyond the limits of human vision
人間の視覚の限界を超えて
we can't tell the difference
私たちには違いがわかりません
Which is faster or slower needs to be distinguished by instruments
どちらが速いか遅いかは計測器によって区別する必要がある
There is also their fluorescent light and aura of the same substance
同じ物質の蛍光やオーラもある
its wavelength is different
その波長は違う
Usually the aura is longer and the fluorescence is shorter
通常、オーラは長く、蛍光は短くなります。
That also requires you to rely on instruments and equipment to control
また、制御するには機器に依存する必要があります
Simultaneously two lights are recorded
2つの光を同時に記録
You know that the one with the long wavelength is the aura
波長が長いのがオーラだということはご存知ですか？
The short wavelength is fluorescence
波長が短いのが蛍光です
It can be divided from these two ways
この2通りに分けられます
Sorry to ask Professor Lin again
リン先生に再度質問して申し訳ありません。
So about the Liao legacy lamp we talked about just now
それで、先ほど話したリャオの伝統的なランプについてです。
That is to say, too strong will affect the eyes
つまり、強すぎると目に悪影響を及ぼします。
To make the lights in our house the best is to say
家の照明を最高のものにするためには、次のように言います。
Use about how much brightness like this
明るさはこのくらいにしてください
For the upper half of the eyes and then bright enough thank you
目の上半分だけ明るくしていただきありがとうございます
it's very important
それは非常に重要です
I'm not very clear about this
これについてはよくわかりません
You might ask your doctor for a better understanding
より深い理解を得るために医師に尋ねることもできます
Because we need different brightness for different occasions
状況に応じて異なる明るさが必要なため
Right, for example, our weaknesses don't need to be very bright
そう、たとえば、私たちの弱点はそれほど明るい必要はないのです。
because it's time to sleep
寝る時間だから
but the office
しかしオフィス
because we want to see something
私たちは何かを見たいから
be bright with me
私と一緒に明るくなってください
But the human eye has a limit
でも人間の目には限界がある
Ask the ophthalmologist about the limit
限界については眼科医に聞いてください
may be clearer
より明確になるかもしれません
makes sense thank you
意味はわかります、ありがとう
OK
OK
Our K-A mates really thank you
K-Aの仲間たち、本当にありがとう
then our first thank you
それでは最初に感謝します
This wonderful interview with Dr. Chen
チェン博士へのこの素晴らしいインタビュー
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました